<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xml:lang="en-GB" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>tag:www.gov.uk,2005:/government/announcements</id>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.gov.uk/"/>
  <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://www.gov.uk/government/announcements.atom"/>
  <title>Announcements on GOV.UK</title>
  <author>
    <name>HM Government</name>
  </author>
  <updated>2014-07-29T14:55:30+01:00</updated>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:www.gov.uk,2005:AnnouncementPresenter/252177</id>
    <published>2014-07-29T14:55:30+01:00</published>
    <updated>2014-07-29T14:55:30+01:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/overnight-and-weekend-closures-for-bridge-expansion-and-strengthening-work-on-m1-junction-24-leicestershire"/>
    <title>Press release: Overnight and weekend closures for bridge expansion and strengthening work on M1 junction 24, Leicestershire</title>
    <category label="Press release" term="Press release"/>
    <summary>A series of overnight and weekend closures on part of junction 24 of the M1 in Leicestershire starts on Monday 4 August for seven weeks.
</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class="govspeak"&gt;&lt;p&gt;The south bridge of the junction is being altered to accommodate a third lane as part of a £6 million Pinch Point scheme to improve capacity, but needs to be strengthened and re-waterproofed first.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the first six weeks the bridge will be closed overnight only, with narrow lanes in place during the day. There will then be two full weekend closures over the weekends of 12 to 15 September and 19 to 22 September. Both weekend closures take place 24/7 from 8pm on the Friday evening to 6am on the Monday morning. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The closures will affect M1 southbound, A453 southbound or A6 northbound traffic heading to East Midlands Airport as well as A453 and A6 traffic heading to the A50 westbound. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Highways Agency Project Manager Rob Edwards said:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;This work will lead to improved capacity and better traffic flow around junction 24 as well as prolong the life of the bridge but for that to happen safely and efficiently we need to close the bridge first.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;We have timed it so the majority of the work takes place in the summer holidays when traffic flows are lighter, and the bulk of the closures take place overnight when traffic is lighter still.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;We advise road users to allow extra time for their journeys during this work, particularly if they have a flight to catch.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p class="last-child"&gt;We would also like to advise people that some of the work, particularly the waterproofing, is weather dependent and can only be carried out in the dry. There may therefore be times the closures do not go ahead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The times of the overnight closures will vary depending on traffic flows, but the earliest time the bridge will close will be 8pm and the latest time it will re-open will be 6am.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During the closures traffic will be diverted southbound on the M1 to junction 23 where it will turn around and head north, leaving the M1 at junction 23a. A separate signed diversion will be in place for non-motorway traffic. Road users are advised to allow at least an extra 15 minutes for their journey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Highways Agency and its contractors have liaised with a number of stakeholders about the closures including East Midlands Airport, Donington Park, public transport operators, local authorities and a number of local businesses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The £6million M1 junction 24 scheme will see the construction of a new carriageway in the middle of the junction to remove traffic travelling from the A50 to the M1 southbound from the roundabout and instead redirect it to the entry slip road at M1 junction 23a via the A453.The work is due to end early in 2015.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People can find out more about the scheme, including regular updates about traffic management and diversions on the Agency’s &lt;a rel="external" href="http://www.highways.gov.uk/roads/road-projects/a453-widening-m1-junction-24-to-a52-nottingham/"&gt;project page&lt;/a&gt; or by calling the Highways Agency Information Line on 0300 123 5000. For real time traffic information the &lt;a rel="external" href="http://www.highways.gov.uk/traffic"&gt;Highways Agency’s website&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id="general-enquiries"&gt;General enquiries&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Members of the public should contact the Highways Agency Information Line on 0300 123 5000.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id="media-enquiries"&gt;Media enquiries&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Journalists should contact the Highways Agency press office on 0844 693 1448 and use the menu to speak to the most appropriate press officer.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:www.gov.uk,2005:AnnouncementPresenter/251605</id>
    <published>2014-07-29T14:48:43+01:00</published>
    <updated>2014-07-29T14:48:43+01:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/grant-to-explore-a-simpler-licensing-system-in-england"/>
    <title>News story: Grant to explore a simpler licensing system in England</title>
    <category label="News story" term="News story"/>
    <summary>A grant from the Better Regulation Delivery Office will help explore how England's complex licensing system can be simplified.</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class="govspeak"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Cornwall Council is to examine how the complex licensing system in England can be simplified after being awarded a grant from the Better Regulation Delivery Office.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The pathfinder project, the only one in England, will explore the possibility of creating a new licensing blueprint, with the aim of creating a single business licence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the moment, businesses have to apply to their local authority for a variety of licences. The aim of this project is to examine what changes councils need to make for it to be possible for a single business licence to be issued on a licence-for-life basis. This would simplify the process of setting up businesses and make it easier for businesses to work with councils.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Business minister Matthew Hancock said: “This Government is ripping out the red tape that holds firms back. We’ve scrapped over 1,000 regulations, saving firms £1.5 billion and we’re on track to be the first government in modern history to leave office with fewer regulations than when we came in. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I am delighted that a simplified licensing system is being examined by Cornwall County Council; this would help free businesses from unnecessary bureaucracy and enable them to focus on creating growth and jobs.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The grant will give Cornwall Council the opportunity to map out existing licensing workflows and understand what changes would be needed to deliver the objective of a single business licence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Various services within Cornwall Council issue around 8,000 to 10,000 business authorisations a year. This includes services such as licensing, food and health and safety, environmental protection, street works, housing, Cornwall Fire &amp;amp; Rescue Service, trading standards and registration. Having to make several applications to a number of various council services can impact on the local economy and inhibit growth.   &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cornwall Council head of public health and protection Allan Hampshire said: “The project is expected to take six months and will include mapping a typical set of activities for both start-up and established businesses. We will also want to work with local businesses and trade associations to better understand their needs in terms of a simplified licensing system.  We will be exploring options that will work better for councils and businesses such as a single licensing application form, a council licensing single point of contact, online accessibility and flexible payment options.” &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:www.gov.uk,2005:AnnouncementPresenter/252171</id>
    <published>2014-07-29T14:46:58+01:00</published>
    <updated>2014-07-29T14:46:58+01:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/home-office-rewards-police-innovation-with-50-million"/>
    <title>News story: Home Office rewards police innovation with £50 million</title>
    <category label="News story" term="News story"/>
    <summary>All forces in England and Wales benefit from Police Innovation Fund</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class="govspeak"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Every police force in England and Wales will receive a share of a £50 million Home Office fund for projects aimed at transforming policing through innovation and collaboration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The successful schemes include investment in body-worn camera, groundbreaking forensics techniques and joint working between the police and fire service.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Forces were awarded money for new approaches to tackle anti-social behaviour and rural crime; a project to help young runaways; and work to improve the way the police interact with people with mental health problems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="new-ideas"&gt;New ideas&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Policing Minister Mike Penning said:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I am delighted that every police force in the country showed such a positive, forward-thinking attitude and came to us with new ideas and ways of working.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;It meant we could allocate £50 million to some really innovative projects and I am already looking forward to visiting forces and seeing the results.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p class="last-child"&gt;Crime has fallen by more than 10 per cent under this government. I believe we can help the police do their job even better by encouraging them to embrace new technology and build on ideas coming from the grass roots.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Police Innovation Fund is in its first full year of operation and up to £50 million will be allocated every 12 months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Earlier this year, the Home Office made a precursor fund of £20 million available to Police and Crime Commissioners.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each of the 43 police forces in England and Wales will benefit from the Fund this year. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="innovative"&gt;Innovative&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Among the most innovative of the 85 proposals to receive funding this time were:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A joint bid of £431,000 by Nottinghamshire and Lancashire Police to reduce the processing time for a DNA profile from four or five days to two hours.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Eight forces – Bedfordshire, Nottinghamshire, the Met, Hampshire, Durham, City of London, Merseyside and North Wales – will share more than £4 million to spend on body worn camera technology.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Metropolitan Police successfully bid for £113,000 to help develop a new spray which will be able to quickly identify body fluids at crime scenes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:www.gov.uk,2005:AnnouncementPresenter/252141</id>
    <published>2014-07-29T14:30:29+01:00</published>
    <updated>2014-07-29T14:30:29+01:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/government-publishes-response-to-consultation-on-the-provision-of-childcare-accounts-in-tax-free-childcare"/>
    <title>News story: Government publishes response to consultation on the provision of childcare accounts in Tax-Free Childcare</title>
    <category label="News story" term="News story"/>
    <summary>Tax-Free Childcare scheme was announced at Budget 2013, and will be available to up to 1.9 million working families.</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class="govspeak"&gt;&lt;p&gt;The government has today published its response to a further &lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/consultations/tax-free-childcare-consultation-on-childcare-account-provision"&gt;consultation on the delivery of childcare accounts&lt;/a&gt; within the Tax-Free Childcare scheme. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After carefully considering the responses to this consultation alongside the responses to the previous consultation, and the evidence on all of the options for delivering accounts, the government has decided that National Savings and Investment (NS&amp;amp;I) will be the scheme’s account provider, working in partnership with Her Majesty’s Revenue and Customs (HMRC). &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Tax-Free Childcare scheme was announced at Budget 2013, and will be available to up to 1.9 million working families, providing 20% support for childcare costs up to £10,000 per year for each child. As such, it will be worth up to £2,000 per child per year. The government is committed to introducing Tax-Free Childcare in autumn 2015 and the scheme will be rolled out to all families with children under the age of 12 within the first year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Parents will qualify for the scheme if all parents in a household are in work, with income less than £150,000 a year, and are not already receiving support through tax credits or Universal Credit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class="call-to-action"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re a parent and want to find out more about the Tax-Free Childcare scheme, here’s the &lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/tax-free-childcare-10-things-parents-should-know"&gt;top ten facts&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:www.gov.uk,2005:AnnouncementPresenter/232929</id>
    <published>2014-07-28T09:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2014-07-29T14:00:58+01:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/driving-licence-fees-to-fall"/>
    <title>Press release: Driving licence fees to fall</title>
    <category label="Press release" term="Press release"/>
    <summary>Driving licence fees are set to fall by up to 32% under plans announced today (28 July 2014) by Chief Secretary to the Treasury, Danny Alexander, and Transport Minister Claire Perry.</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Updated:&lt;/em&gt; Driving licence fees infographic added.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="govspeak"&gt;&lt;p&gt;The proposals are contained in a &lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/consultations/driver-licensing-fees--2"&gt;public consultation&lt;/a&gt; on driver licensing fees. The consultation sets out a proposed reduction in driving licence fees of 32% for digital transactions and 15% for paper applications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As part of the proposals, drivers who apply online for their first driving licence would see the fee drop from £50 to £34.  Drivers who renew their licence after 10 years would see the fee drop from £20 to £14. All driver tachograph cards would fall from £38 to £32.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chief Secretary to the Treasury, Danny Alexander said:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p class="last-child"&gt;I have been working hard to drive savings across the whole public sector and it’s great to see the benefit of these efficiencies feed through to drivers and businesses pockets. What the DVLA have shown today is that you can do more for less.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Transport Minister Claire Perry said:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p class="last-child"&gt;The cost of driving can be significant, especially for new drivers. I’m pleased to say that we are planning to save drivers £18m a year by cutting licence fees, thanks to the DVLA making significant savings to their running costs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The proposals are set to save drivers nearly £18 million and the industry around £2 million every year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class="image embedded"&gt;&lt;div class="img"&gt;&lt;img alt="Driving licence fees infographic" src="https://assets.digital.cabinet-office.gov.uk/government/uploads/system/uploads/image_data/file/29157/Driving_licence_fees_final_Twitter.jpeg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;DVLA is currently reviewing all the fees they charge to motorists and the consultation launched today is the first step in this ongoing review.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/consultations/driver-licensing-fees--2"&gt;consultation&lt;/a&gt; closes on 25 August 2014.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-Ends-&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Notes to editors &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;View the current &lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/driving-licence-fees"&gt;driving licence fees&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Subject to the consultation and parliamentary process the new fees are planned to come into force by 31 October 2014.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The consultation is the first phase in the DVLA review of their fees.  The second phase will involve a comprehensive review of the DVLA’s funding and will focus on the way they deliver their services to customers in light of the introduction of further digital services.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;div class="contact postal-address" id="contact_1075"&gt;
  &lt;div class="content"&gt;
    &lt;h3&gt;Press office&lt;/h3&gt;

    &lt;div class="vcard contact-inner"&gt;
        &lt;p class="adr"&gt;
&lt;span class="street-address"&gt;DVLA Press Office 
&lt;br&gt;
Longview Road 
&lt;br&gt;
Morriston 
&lt;br&gt;
Swansea &lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;span class="postal-code"&gt;SA6 7JL &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;


        &lt;div class="email-url-number"&gt;
            &lt;p class="email"&gt;
              &lt;span class="type"&gt;Email&lt;/span&gt;
              &lt;a class="email" href="mailto:press.office@dvla.gsi.gov.uk%20"&gt;press.office@dvla.gsi.gov.uk &lt;/a&gt;
            &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p class="tel"&gt;
              &lt;span class="type"&gt;Telephone (only for use by journalists and the media):&lt;/span&gt;
              0300 123 0791 
            &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p class="tel"&gt;
              &lt;span class="type"&gt;Telephone (out of office hours): &lt;/span&gt;
              0300 123 2407 
            &lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;


    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:www.gov.uk,2005:AnnouncementPresenter/252159</id>
    <published>2014-07-29T13:52:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2014-07-29T13:52:00+01:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/support-for-armed-forces-at-wales-office-round-table"/>
    <title>Press release: Support for armed forces at Wales Office round table meeting</title>
    <category label="Press release" term="Press release"/>
    <summary>Baroness Randerson leads discussion on how best to support armed forces in Wales.</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class="govspeak"&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the lead-up to September’s &lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/topical-events/nato-summit-wales-cymru-2014"&gt;NATO Summit&lt;/a&gt; in Newport, support for the armed forces community in Wales was the subject under discussion at the Wales Office this week.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hosted by Wales Office Minister Baroness Jenny Randerson, the event provided a welcome opportunity to discuss issues facing armed forces personnel and veterans. Topics on the agenda included discussions on what more can be done to ensure that our armed forces communities get the support they need.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="baroness-randerson-said"&gt;Baroness Randerson said:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;It was a privilege to host this meeting and in the lead-up to the NATO Summit see the very real support that exists for the armed forces in Wales.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p class="last-child"&gt;Their contribution is immense and I am proud to have a role in ensuring that Wales’ appreciation of them is practically rewarded.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Information on the &lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/policies/fulfilling-the-commitments-of-the-armed-forces-covenant/supporting-pages/armed-forces-covenant"&gt;Armed Forces Covenant&lt;/a&gt; and the support provided across the UK was provided by the Ministry of Defence while a representative of the Welsh Government outlined the support available in Wales.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a rel="external" href="https://www.defencediscountservice.co.uk/"&gt;Defence Discount Service&lt;/a&gt;, which provides the only official discount for the armed forces, gave a presentation on the workings of the Defence Privilege Card. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More than 3,000 national and local businesses have signed up to provide discounts to the 24,000-plus members of the armed forces who have joined the scheme to date. The Baroness was delighted to welcome businesses already offering discounts in Wales and looks forward to welcoming many further participants. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also in attendance were representatives from a range of organisations who support the armed forces and discussions on current and future support were positive. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class="call-to-action"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For updates on the 2014 Nato Summit follow the official summit Twitter account &lt;a rel="external" href="https://twitter.com/NATOWales"&gt;@NATOWales&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:www.gov.uk,2005:AnnouncementPresenter/252151</id>
    <published>2014-07-29T13:41:54+01:00</published>
    <updated>2014-07-29T13:41:54+01:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/baroness-kramer-opens-folkestone-west-station-improvements"/>
    <title>News story: Baroness Kramer opens Folkestone West station improvements</title>
    <category label="News story" term="News story"/>
    <summary>£1.7 million investment in station building and car park.</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class="govspeak"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Transport minister Baroness Kramer visited Kent today (29 July 2015) to see how £1.7 million of investment has transformed Folkestone West station, providing more comfort and convenience for passengers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Baroness Kramer officially opened the new facilities, which include a new waiting room and booking office, and an expanded car park providing an extra 200 spaces. Additional bike racks have also been installed, and the customer information system has been upgraded.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Baroness Kramer said:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;These improvements at Folkestone West will transform the passenger experience, providing greater comfort and convenience, and making it easier for people to travel to work and leisure opportunities.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p class="last-child"&gt;As part of our long-term economic plan, we have invested £1.7 million at this station and we are committing £38 billion over the next 5 years to improve and maintain the UK’s rail network, in order to meet the needs of the increasing numbers of passengers using the railways, and the work at Folkestone West is a great example of this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Work to the car park started earlier this year and has boosted the number of available spaces to 270, in order to accommodate the increasing number of passengers using the station now and in the future. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The station also has a new forecourt area with a customer drop-off point, and a new ticket office designed to meet accessibility requirements. A new ticket vending machine and information monitors have been installed, along with an upgraded public address system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Charles Horton, managing director of Southeastern, said: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The new car park and booking hall at Folkestone West provides a more welcoming station environment for our passengers and offers us room for growth.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p class="last-child"&gt;We chose to develop the facilities at this station in response to calls from passengers for more parking spaces and have worked with our industry partners to deliver facilities that are fit for the future. At a time when rail passenger numbers are rocketing and we’re expanding high speed services through the station, this investment offers a welcome boost to Folkestone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The work has been funded by the Department for Transport and Network Rail through the &lt;a rel="external" href="http://www.networkrail.co.uk/nsip/"&gt;National Stations Improvement Programme&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a rel="external" href="http://www.networkrail.co.uk/aspx/12458.aspx"&gt;Station Commercial Project Fund&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;abbr title="Station Commercial Project Fund"&gt;SCPF&lt;/abbr&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During her visit to Folkestone, Baroness Kramer also travelled on Southeastern’s high speed train to see first-hand how the service is providing improved connections to London and benefiting the local economy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class="contact" id="contact_1019"&gt;
  &lt;div class="content"&gt;
    &lt;h3&gt;Rail media enquiries&lt;/h3&gt;

    &lt;div class="vcard contact-inner"&gt;

        &lt;div class="email-url-number"&gt;
            &lt;p class="tel"&gt;
              &lt;span class="type"&gt;Press enquiries&lt;/span&gt;
              020 7944 4671
            &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p class="tel"&gt;
              &lt;span class="type"&gt;Out of hours&lt;/span&gt;
              020 7944 4292
            &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p class="tel"&gt;
              &lt;span class="type"&gt;Public enquiries&lt;/span&gt;
              0300 330 3000
            &lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;


    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:www.gov.uk,2005:AnnouncementPresenter/249131</id>
    <published>2014-07-18T12:45:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2014-07-29T12:47:18+01:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/malaysia-airlines-flight-mh17-uk-government-response"/>
    <title>News story: Malaysia Airlines flight MH17: UK government response</title>
    <category label="News story" term="News story"/>
    <summary>Latest news and travel advice relating to flight MH17, which crashed in Ukraine on 17 July 2014. This page will be updated regularly.</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Updated:&lt;/em&gt; Added joint call from 28 July.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="govspeak"&gt;&lt;h2 id="latest-news-and-statements"&gt;Latest news and statements&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id="july"&gt;28 July&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/joint-call-with-obama-merkel-hollande-and-renzi"&gt;PM joint call with President Obama, Angela Merkel, President Hollande and Prime Minister Renzi&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3 id="july-1"&gt;21 July&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/statement-on-mh17-disaster-and-israel-and-gaza-national-security-council-meeting-21-july"&gt;Statement on MH17 disaster: National Security Council Meeting&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/speeches/prime-ministers-statement-on-ukraine-and-gaza"&gt;The Prime Minister’s statement on Ukraine to the House of Commons&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3 id="july-2"&gt;20 July&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/pm-call-with-president-putin-on-the-flight-mh17-disaster"&gt;PM call with President Putin on the flight MH17 disaster&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/statement-on-the-flight-mh17-disaster-foreign-secretarys-meeting-20-july"&gt;Statement on the flight MH17 disaster: Foreign Secretary’s meeting&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/pm-calls-with-chancellor-merkel-and-president-hollande-on-flight-mh17-disaster"&gt;PM calls with Chancellor Merkel and President Hollande on flight MH17 disaster&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/mh17-air-disaster-article-by-david-cameron"&gt;MH17 air disaster: an article from David Cameron&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3 id="july-3"&gt;19 July&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/russian-ambassador-summoned-to-fco-over-flight-mh17"&gt;Russian Ambassador summoned to FCO over flight MH17&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/statement-on-the-mh17-disaster-investigation-and-pm-calls-to-other-leaders"&gt;Statement on the MH17 disaster investigation and PM calls to other leaders&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3 id="july-4"&gt;18 July&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/pm-call-with-president-obama-on-flight-mh17-disaster"&gt;PM call with President Obama on flight MH17 disaster&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/government-statement-on-the-malaysia-airlines-flight-mh17"&gt;Government statement on the Malaysia Airlines flight MH17&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/pm-calls-other-leaders-to-discuss-flight-mh17-disaster"&gt;PM calls other leaders to discuss flight MH17 disaster&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel="external" href="http://www.un.org/News/Press/docs/2014/sc11480.doc.htm"&gt;United Nations Security Council press statement on Malaysian plane crash&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/speeches/this-is-a-dark-moment-for-the-international-community"&gt;Statement by UK Ambassador Lyall Grant to the UN Security Council meeting on the situation in Ukraine&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/speeches/pm-statement-on-malaysia-airlines-flight-mh17"&gt;PM statement on Malaysia Airlines flight MH17&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3 id="july-5"&gt;17 July&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/foreign-secretary-we-believe-british-nationals-were-on-board-mh17"&gt;Foreign Secretary: We believe British nationals were on board MH17&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2 id="ukraine-travel-advice"&gt;Ukraine travel advice&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read &lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/foreign-travel-advice/ukraine"&gt;updated travel advice relating to Ukraine&lt;/a&gt; from the Foreign &amp;amp; Commonwealth Office.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class="call-to-action"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;British nationals who are concerned a friend or relative may be involved in the flight MH17 disaster should contact the Foreign Office on 020 7008 1500.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id="social-media-to-follow"&gt;Social media to follow&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To keep up to date with the latest statements and advice on Twitter, follow:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a rel="external" href="http://twitter.com/number10gov"&gt;@Number10gov&lt;/a&gt; – UK Prime Minister&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
&lt;a rel="external" href="http://twitter.com/foreignoffice"&gt;@ForeignOffice&lt;/a&gt; – Foreign &amp;amp; Commonwealth Office&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
&lt;a rel="external" href="http://twitter.com/ukinukraine"&gt;@UKinUkraine&lt;/a&gt; - British Embassy Kyiv&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:www.gov.uk,2005:AnnouncementPresenter/252122</id>
    <published>2014-07-29T12:17:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2014-07-29T12:17:00+01:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/revised-guidelines-for-malaria-prevention-in-travellers-from-the-uk--2"/>
    <title>News story: Revised guidelines for malaria prevention in travellers from the UK</title>
    <category label="News story" term="News story"/>
    <summary>Guidelines include information on general malaria prevention, country recommendations and anti-malarial drug information.</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class="govspeak"&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Public Health England (&lt;abbr title="Public Health England"&gt;PHE&lt;/abbr&gt;) Advisory Committee on Malaria Prevention (&lt;abbr title="Advisory Committee on Malaria Prevention"&gt;ACMP&lt;/abbr&gt;) has published revised Guidelines for Malaria Prevention in Travellers from the UK.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The guidelines are primarily intended for use by healthcare workers who provide advice to travellers but may also be of interest to prospective travellers themselves. They cover crucial aspects of malaria prevention including the ABCD principles:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Awareness of risk&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bite prevention&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Chemoprophylaxis (antimalarial tablets)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Diagnose promptly and treat without delay&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Professor Peter Chiodini, malaria expert at the &lt;abbr title="Public Health England"&gt;PHE&lt;/abbr&gt; Malaria Reference Laboratory, said:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p class="last-child"&gt;The guidelines answer frequently asked questions, and include advice for the prevention of malaria in the presence of co-existing medical conditions, such as epilepsy.  Key revisions to the guidelines have been made in the following contexts: general malaria prevention, country recommendations, anti-malarial drug information and special risk groups.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dr Jane Jones, travel and migrant health expert at &lt;abbr title="Public Health England"&gt;PHE&lt;/abbr&gt; said: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;In 2013, there were 1,501 cases of imported malaria reported in the UK. Malaria remains an important travel-associated infection, which particularly affects people travelling to visit friends and relatives, especially in Africa and Asia.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p class="last-child"&gt;Anyone who is travelling to a country where malaria is present should seek pre-travel advice from their general practice or travel health clinic about taking appropriate anti-malarial medication and other necessary measures to protect themselves, especially &lt;a rel="external" href="http://www.nathnac.org/travel/misc/travellers_mos.htm"&gt;insect bite avoidance&lt;/a&gt;. Severe complications of malaria can be rapidly fatal. Anyone with symptoms (usually flu-like or a fever), either while abroad or after they return home, must get immediate medical help.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/malaria-prevention-guidelines-for-travellers-from-the-uk"&gt;revised malaria guidelines&lt;/a&gt; and general information about &lt;a rel="external" href="http://www.hpa.org.uk/infections/topics_az/malaria/default.htm."&gt;malaria&lt;/a&gt; are available on the &lt;abbr title="Public Health England"&gt;PHE&lt;/abbr&gt; website.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:www.gov.uk,2005:AnnouncementPresenter/252098</id>
    <published>2014-07-29T12:16:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2014-07-29T12:16:00+01:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/new-immigration-measures-announced"/>
    <title>News story: New immigration measures announced</title>
    <category label="News story" term="News story"/>
    <summary>A new crackdown on the abuse of student visas was announced today – as further measures of the Immigration Act came into force. </summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class="govspeak"&gt;&lt;h2 id="tackling-student-visa-abuse"&gt;Tackling student visa abuse&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From November, tougher rules will be imposed on universities and colleges who sponsor international students to study in the UK.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Currently, educational institutions can enjoy Highly Trusted Sponsor status if the Home Office rejects 20% or fewer student applications as being invalid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But that figure will be cut to 10% in November after a three-month grace period for colleges and universities to re-examine and improve their admissions procedures. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If more than one in 10 applications are being rejected from November onwards, educational institutions could lose their right to bring in new students from overseas. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The change will ensure all institutions are playing their part in administering immigration rules to enjoy the benefits of bringing in foreign students.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The new student rules were announced as further measures in the government’s flagship Immigration Act came into force, including laws cracking down on sham marriages and stripping illegal immigrants of driving licences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Home Secretary Theresa May said:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p class="last-child"&gt;We are building an immigration system that is fair to British citizens and legitimate migrants, but tough on those who abuse it or flout the law.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p class="last-child"&gt;The Immigration Act is a landmark piece of legislation that will make Britain a less attractive place for those who come here for the wrong reasons, and will allow us to remove more people when they have no right to remain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p class="last-child"&gt;We will always act when we see abuse of our immigration system. And that is why we are tightening the rules to cut out abuse in the student visa system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p class="last-child"&gt;These reforms are helping to deliver what we have always promised — to build an immigration system that truly works in the national interest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id="new-measures"&gt;New measures&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Key measures from the Immigration Act which are now in force include: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Introducing enhanced duties for registrars to report suspected sham marriages and civil partnerships;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Creating new powers to streamline the recovery of illegal working penalties;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Establishing the ability to remove harmful individuals before their appeals are heard if there is no risk of serious irreversible harm;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Strengthening requirements for the courts to have regard to Parliament’s view of the public interest in immigration cases raising Article 8 - making clear the right to a family life is not to be regarded as absolute and unqualified; and&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Introducing new powers to revoke the driving licences of known illegal immigrants.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel="external" href="http://www.legislation.gov.uk/uksi/2014/1820/contents/made"&gt;Details of Immigration Act measures commenced today&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:www.gov.uk,2005:AnnouncementPresenter/252112</id>
    <published>2014-07-29T11:19:18+01:00</published>
    <updated>2014-07-29T11:19:18+01:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/britain-to-provide-new-assistance-to-combat-ebola-in-west-africa"/>
    <title>Press release: Britain to provide new assistance to combat Ebola in West Africa</title>
    <category label="Press release" term="Press release"/>
    <summary>The UK will provide medical support and supplies to contain the spread of Ebola in West Africa, International Development Secretary Justine Greening announced on Friday 25 July.</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class="govspeak"&gt;&lt;p&gt;A new £2 million package of assistance will be made available immediately to partners including the International Federation of the Red Cross (IFRC) and Médecins Sans Frontières that are operating in Sierra Leone and Liberia to tackle the outbreak.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This funding will:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fill critical gaps in the front-line response by providing technical staff including epidemiologists, clinicians, information managers and logistics managers for six months&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Improve public understanding of the disease by increasing media messaging and direct engagement with communities, including women’s groups&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Expand the investigation, tracing and treatment of  new cases&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Provide safe and dignified burial to the deceased.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Justine Greening said:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p class="last-child"&gt;This Ebola outbreak poses a serious public health risk to West Africa.
Britain is working with the countries affected and the international community to ensure that the outbreak is contained and help reaches those in need.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This latest round of funding is in addition to support the UK has been providing since the outbreak of the disease in February 2014.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Sierra Leone and Liberia the UK has been supporting agencies to increase awareness and understanding of  the disease within the community, to improve treatment for those infected, and to prevent its spread within and across borders. This includes working with the WHO to train health workers and provide the supplies they need to tackle the outbreak.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The UK has also funded initiatives to improve public information, including radio messaging programmes, on the outbreak in Sierra Leone to help control the spread of the disease.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Liberia the UK has provided chlorine and other materials for hygiene and sanitising. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class="contact" id="contact_5"&gt;
  &lt;div class="content"&gt;
    &lt;h3&gt;Press office&lt;/h3&gt;

    &lt;div class="vcard contact-inner"&gt;

        &lt;div class="email-url-number"&gt;
            &lt;p class="email"&gt;
              &lt;span class="type"&gt;Email&lt;/span&gt;
              &lt;a class="email" href="mailto:pressoffice@dfid.gov.uk"&gt;pressoffice@dfid.gov.uk&lt;/a&gt;
            &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p class="tel"&gt;
              &lt;span class="type"&gt;Telephone&lt;/span&gt;
              020 7023 0600 
            &lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;

        &lt;p class="comments"&gt;Follow the DFID Press office on Twitter - @DFID_Press&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:www.gov.uk,2005:AnnouncementPresenter/252103</id>
    <published>2014-07-29T11:06:09+01:00</published>
    <updated>2014-07-29T11:06:09+01:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.gov.uk/government/speeches/civil-service-commission-triennial-review-announced"/>
    <title>Statement to Parliament: Civil Service Commission: triennial review announced</title>
    <category label="Statement to Parliament" term="Statement to Parliament"/>
    <summary>Lord Wallace of Saltaire announced a triennial review of the Civil Service Commission and set out the terms of reference.</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class="govspeak"&gt;&lt;p&gt;In accordance with the guidance on triennial reviews for public bodies, the government has asked Sir Gerry Grimstone to lead a review of the &lt;a rel="external" href="http://civilservicecommission.independent.gov.uk/"&gt;Civil Service Commission&lt;/a&gt;. This will be the first review of the Commission’s status and role since its creation in statute in the &lt;a rel="external" href="http://www.legislation.gov.uk/ukpga/2010/25/contents"&gt;Constitutional Reform and Governance Act 2010&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The review’s purpose will be to establish the continuing need for the Commission, and to examine its scope of responsibilities. In particular the review will consider the Commission’s current and any possible future role in assuring the following aspects of the civil service: leadership and stewardship; capabilities; performance management; and upholding standards. The review’s terms of reference have been placed in the library of the House.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sir Gerry will seek advice and challenge from a wide range of individuals, including ex-ministers, ex-senior civil servants, and the government’s non-executive directors. The review will report in the autumn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="terms-of-reference"&gt;Terms of reference&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Civil Service Commissioners were first appointed a year after the Northcote-Trevelyan report of 1854 as a guarantor of its principles of professionalism, impartiality and meritocracy. The Commission was given statutory underpinning in the Constitutional Reform and Governance Act of 2010. The triennial review should swiftly verify that the requirement for the Commission as set out in that Act persists.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It should then review whether its remit should be extended or amended to ensure that the challenges the civil service faces today are being properly addressed. This would include, but not be limited to, the following areas: capabilities; upholding standards; performance management; and leadership and stewardship.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:www.gov.uk,2005:AnnouncementPresenter/252082</id>
    <published>2014-07-29T10:41:32+01:00</published>
    <updated>2014-07-29T10:41:32+01:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/convenience-culture-drives-high-street-revival"/>
    <title>Press release: ‘Convenience culture’ drives high street revival</title>
    <category label="Press release" term="Press release"/>
    <summary>New high streets study reveals town centres are meeting the changing demands of consumers. </summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class="govspeak"&gt;&lt;p&gt;A new &lt;a rel="external" href="http://thegreatbritishhighstreet.co.uk/pdf/GBHS-HighStreetReport.pdf"&gt;in-depth study&lt;/a&gt; into the state of British high streets has revealed how town centres are adapting to meet the changing demands of the nation’s consumers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Researchers at the University of Southampton reveal how ‘fundamental’ changes to Britain’s ‘convenience culture’ are transforming the way we shop and bringing new business into town.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;New High Streets Minister Penny Mordaunt today (29 July 2014) welcomed the study’s findings as proof the country’s most dynamic and flexible town centres were experiencing a retail resurgence despite the competitive pressures of internet shopping and out-of-town stores.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It comes as the Department for Communities and Local Government and leading retail experts step up the summer search to find the best high streets in Britain.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In one of the most definitive studies into consumer habits ever conducted in Britain, the University of Southampton Retail Research Group discovered there has been a ‘fundamental shift’ in what consumers mean by ‘convenience’ shopping.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Throughout the 1980’s and 1990’s this was defined as one-stop shopping in big out-of-town developments but increasingly convenience means ‘topping up’ the groceries in local stores.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Convenience retail in town centres/high streets, both independently and corporately owned, has experienced significant growth over the past 15 years, a growth sustained during the economic crisis and subsequent period of austerity,” the report finds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That trend is expected to continue over the next 5 years, with convenience stores accounting for a quarter of the entire grocery market by 2019. Over the same period the market share for superstores is expected to fall from 42% to 34.9%. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The study also concludes there has been a ‘modest resurgence’ in specialist retailers such as ‘artisanal bakers, butchers and tea and coffee merchants’ on high streets were independent stores stand alongside big high street names.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the same time retailers are exploiting opportunities created by on-line shopping – particularly with the rise in click and collect buying. Within 5 years, 7 out of 10 on-line shoppers will prefer to collect goods themselves rather than risk missing a delivery at home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The study also finds the ‘leisure aspect of shopping trips is a significant driver of footfall’ and that high streets that include a good range of cafes, bars, restaurants not only increase the ‘dwell time but the average spent during trips to town’.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The University of Southampton study suggests that the long-term shifts towards leisure, health and beauty services – such as nail salons, hair dressers and gyms – will continue. While consumer spending on leisure is projected to increase over the next 10 years, spending on ‘recession-related’ retail, like pawnbrokers and betting shops, will slow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“New relationships are being established in town centres and high streets, creating opportunities and contributing to their resilience,” the study concludes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Minister Penny Mordaunt said: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p class="last-child"&gt;This report shows our high streets to be adaptable, creative and resilient. The Great British High Street competition is a chance to showcase those strengths, to bust myths about the long-term future of our town centres and to reward the local talent, team-work and energy that goes into making our high streets great places to visit, work or live.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Simon Roberts, Managing Director, Health and Beauty UK and Republic of Ireland, Alliance Boots, and Future High Streets Forum Co-Chairman said:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;We welcome the report’s findings and continue to work with the Future High Street Forum to drive this agenda forward. High streets are changing with clear evidence of effective business engagement and leadership making a real difference. Town centres matter to our customers – they are at the heart of many communities, providing identity as well as growth, development and jobs.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p class="last-child"&gt;The Great British High Street competition provides an excellent opportunity to recognise and celebrate some of the fantastic work being delivered at local level to strengthen town centre prosperity. We are delighted to work with the Future High Street Forum member organisations to offer our support to high streets across the UK, together making them great places for our customers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a rel="external" href="http://thegreatbritishhighstreet.co.uk/high-street-of-the-year-award"&gt;competition&lt;/a&gt; is being run by the &lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/groups/future-high-streets-forum"&gt;Future High Streets Forum&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a rel="external" href="https://www.atcm.org/"&gt;Association of Town and City Management&lt;/a&gt; until 30 August.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are 7 categories: city centres, town centres, market towns, coastal communities, villages, parades and London. Winners will receive a share of prize money and support worth £50,000, provided by Forum sponsors, as well as access to a tailored package of mentoring from industry experts. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This could range from one to one coaching to advice on creating business plans to attending workshops on digital marketing. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="further-information"&gt;Further information&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The University of Southampton report can be viewed at on &lt;a rel="external" href="http://thegreatbritishhighstreet.co.uk/"&gt;the Great British High Street website&lt;/a&gt; alongside high street best practice and guidance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recent &lt;a rel="external" href="http://www.deloitte.com/view/en_GB/uk/industries/consumer-business/consumer-review/5ae671d7b88f4410VgnVCM2000003356f70aRCRD.htm"&gt;high street research&lt;/a&gt; by Deloitte, (April 2014) showed the high street remains the number one destination for shops, services and leisure, compared to online and out-of-town.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel="external" href="http://www.gfk.com/uk/news-and-events/press-room/press-releases/pages/may-sees-a-three-point-rise-in-consumer-confidence.aspx"&gt;Consumer confidence&lt;/a&gt; in May 2014 was at the highest level since April 2005.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Winners will receive a share of prize money and support provided by Forum sponsors Boots, Costa, M&amp;amp;S, and BIRA. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The University of Southampton study was funded by the &lt;a rel="external" href="http://www.esrc.ac.uk/"&gt;Economic and Social Research Council (ESRC)&lt;/a&gt; which funds research into the big social and economic questions of the day. Its research informs public policies and helps make businesses, voluntary bodies and other organisations more effective. The Council is an independent organisation, established by Royal Charter in 1965.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class="contact postal-address" id="contact_40"&gt;
  &lt;div class="content"&gt;
    &lt;h3&gt;Office address and general enquiries&lt;/h3&gt;

    &lt;div class="vcard contact-inner"&gt;
        &lt;p class="adr"&gt;
&lt;span class="street-address"&gt;Eland House
&lt;br&gt;
Bressenden Place
&lt;br&gt;
London&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;span class="postal-code"&gt;SW1E 5DU&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;


        &lt;div class="email-url-number"&gt;
            &lt;p class="contact_form_url"&gt;
              &lt;span class="type"&gt;Contact form&lt;/span&gt;
              &lt;a href="http://forms.communities.gov.uk/"&gt;http://forms.communiti...&lt;/a&gt;
            &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p class="tel"&gt;
              &lt;span class="type"&gt;General enquiries:  please use this number if you are a member of the public&lt;/span&gt;
              030 3444 0000
            &lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;


    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="contact" id="contact_171"&gt;
  &lt;div class="content"&gt;
    &lt;h3&gt;Media enquiries&lt;/h3&gt;

    &lt;div class="vcard contact-inner"&gt;

        &lt;div class="email-url-number"&gt;
            &lt;p class="email"&gt;
              &lt;span class="type"&gt;Email&lt;/span&gt;
              &lt;a class="email" href="mailto:communications-newsdesk@communities.gsi.gov.uk"&gt;communications-newsdesk@communities.gsi.gov.uk&lt;/a&gt;
            &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p class="tel"&gt;
              &lt;span class="type"&gt;Please use this number if you're a journalist wishing to speak to Press Office&lt;/span&gt;
              030 3444 1201
            &lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;


    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:www.gov.uk,2005:AnnouncementPresenter/249128</id>
    <published>2014-07-29T09:58:02+01:00</published>
    <updated>2014-07-29T09:58:02+01:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/lord-livingston-meets-top-exporters-from-the-south-east-region"/>
    <title>News story: Lord Livingston meets top exporters from the south east region</title>
    <category label="News story" term="News story"/>
    <summary>Winners of the 2014 Queen’s Award for Enterprise from the south east celebrated their success at a special event in London hosted by Lord Livingston.</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class="govspeak"&gt;&lt;p&gt;UK Trade &amp;amp; Investment (UKTI) recently (7 July 2014) held an event to recognise the winners of the 2014 Queen’s Award for Enterprise. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;15 winners attended the prestigious event at the Farmer’s Club in London. They were welcomed by Lord Livingston, Minister for Trade &amp;amp; Investment and UKTI South East director Lewis Scott.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lord Livingston, Minister for Trade &amp;amp; Investment, said:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p class="last-child"&gt;With the largest number of Queen’s Award winners in the country, the South East certainly has a lot to celebrate. This event provided a fantastic opportunity for me to speak to some of the region’s best exporters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p class="last-child"&gt;The event highlighted the support provided by UK Trade &amp;amp; Investment and UK Export Finance and I would encourage all companies interested in exporting to find out how government can help their business.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The attendees received information on how they can further increase their exports with the help of UKTI’s services.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="winning-companies"&gt;Winning companies&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Companies from the south east represented at the event included:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a rel="external" href="http://thermometer.co.uk/"&gt;Electronic Temperature Instruments Ltd&lt;/a&gt; -  increased exports to 45% of their turnover&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
&lt;a rel="external" href="http://www.levertonclarke.com/"&gt;Leverton Clarke Ltd&lt;/a&gt; - increased their export sales&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
&lt;a rel="external" href="http://www.oxfordtechnologies.co.uk/"&gt;Oxford Technologies Ltd&lt;/a&gt; -  501% growth in overseas earnings over the last 6 years&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lewis Scott, Regional Director of UKTI South East, said: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p class="last-child"&gt;From a company selling rotary kilns to South America, to a firm supplying edible pulses to Africa, it’s clear that local companies really are blazing a trail for exporters across the South East.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p class="last-child"&gt;I believe there are many more businesses in the area that are ready to sell overseas but who just need some help and guidance before taking the plunge, and UKTI are here to help them do just that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id="queens-awards-for-enterprise"&gt;Queen’s Awards for Enterprise&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Winners of the Queen’s Award receive:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a crystal bowl to mark their achievement by a Royal representative&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;a grant of appointment signed by the Queen and Prime Minister&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;an invite to attend a celebratory reception at Buckingham Palace.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;permission to use the Queen’s Award emblem in their advertising for 5 years&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;div class="call-to-action"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Find out more about &lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/queens-awards-for-enterprise"&gt;previous winners and how to apply for the 2015 awards&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id="contact-us"&gt;Contact us&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;div class="call-to-action"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel="external" href="http://www.greatbusiness.gov.uk/ukti/?utm_source=UKTIHomepage&amp;amp;utm_medium=GOVUK&amp;amp;utm_campaign=EIG"&gt;Book an appointment&lt;/a&gt; with an export adviser if you’re interested in developing your business overseas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:www.gov.uk,2005:AnnouncementPresenter/252090</id>
    <published>2014-07-29T09:52:50+01:00</published>
    <updated>2014-07-29T09:52:50+01:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/fishermen-rescued-from-liferaft-after-9-hours-at-sea"/>
    <title>Press release: Fishermen rescued from liferaft after 9 hours at sea</title>
    <category label="Press release" term="Press release"/>
    <summary>2 fishermen are recovering after spending the day at sea in a liferaft.</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class="govspeak"&gt;&lt;p&gt;They had been fishing 12 miles east of Sunderland when their vessel appeared to hit a submerged object and sank so quickly that they were unable to make a distress call. Their liferaft floated free of their vessel, as it is designed to do, and the pair were able to climb on board.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At 4.40pm on Monday 28 July 2014, the Dutch yacht ‘Jager’ came across the fishermen in their liferaft. They took the two men on board their boat and contacted Humber Coastguard to inform them of what had happened. The Coastguard requested the Hartlepool &lt;abbr title="Royal National Lifeboat Institution"&gt;RNLI&lt;/abbr&gt; lifeboat to launch and they picked the two men up from the yacht and brought them to shore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mike Puplett, Humber Coastguard Watch Manager, said:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Both of the fishermen are now safe and well, although a little shaken by their ordeal. We’d like to thank the Dutch yacht ‘Jager’ which rescued the men and went out of their way to ensure their safety.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;The fishing vessel’s liferaft was a life saver and this incident highlights how important it is to ensure that liferafts are properly maintained and able to float free of the boat should the worst happen. Fishermen should wear personal flotation devices at all times whilst on deck. Even if the liferaft floats free, getting into one is no mean feat, especially if the weather is more volatile than today’s relatively calm seas.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p class="last-child"&gt;Although the liferaft has been drifting for nine hours, we are still hopeful that we will be able to find the wreckage of the boat using our search and rescue information system (SARIS) which is a computer programme that allows us to plot the drift of vessels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;abbr title="Maritime and Coastguard Agency"&gt;MCA&lt;/abbr&gt;’s counter pollution branch and the Marine Accident Investigation Branch have been informed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class="contact" id="contact_1507"&gt;
  &lt;div class="content"&gt;
    &lt;h3&gt;Maritime and Coastguard Agency press office&lt;/h3&gt;

    &lt;div class="vcard contact-inner"&gt;

        &lt;div class="email-url-number"&gt;
            &lt;p class="tel"&gt;
              &lt;span class="type"&gt;Press enquiries&lt;/span&gt;
              023 8032 9401
            &lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;


    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:www.gov.uk,2005:AnnouncementPresenter/251817</id>
    <published>2014-07-29T09:40:14+01:00</published>
    <updated>2014-07-29T09:40:14+01:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/new-polycast-factory-to-enter-automotive-supply-chain-in-mexico"/>
    <title>News story: New Polycast factory to enter automotive supply chain in Mexico</title>
    <category label="News story" term="News story"/>
    <summary>UKTI helps Southampton based casting firm Polycast with its international expansion to develop its first factory in Mexico.</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class="govspeak"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Specialist investment casting firm Polycast will supply the growing automotive market in the Americas region through its latest move. The company have purchased land and property for a new factory in the city of Mexicali. Polycast will join 20 other British companies already manufacturing in the state of Baja California in Mexico.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ian Haddon, Managing Director of Polycast and Chief Operating Officer of Unipol, said:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p class="last-child"&gt;Investing in a manufacturing footprint locally to meet the growth potential of our markets has been fundamental to our success.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Polycast has been receiving support from UK Trade &amp;amp; Investment (UKTI) for over 7 years. This has helped them meet the right contacts to help with their international expansion plans in Mexico.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ian Haddon said,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p class="last-child"&gt;UKTI staff have consistently understood our business and our requirements. They have always been there with excellent quality information and advice. We have capitalised on their extensive relationships in China, India and Mexico. As we develop our next five year growth plan and future geographical and market expansion we will be relying on them again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A delegation of 10 political and business development representatives from the state of Baja California recently visited Polycast’s original foundry in Warsash. They were led by state governor, Mr Francisco Arturo Vega de Lamadrid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ian Haddon said,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The professionalism and joined-up support structure offered by Baja California for overseas investing companies is truly of the highest quality and this made our decision to choose the city of Mexicali an easy one to make.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="new-factory"&gt;New factory&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The new 55,000 square foot facility in the Mexican State of Baja California will open by January 2016. The factory will employ up to 270 employees.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The new factory is expected to generate an extra £20 million turnover for Unipol (Polycast’s joint venture). Unipol, supplys cast turbocharger wheels to the global automotive turbocharger manufacturing industry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="how-ukti-helped"&gt;How UKTI helped&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Polycast has made extensive use of UKTI’s overseas networks by participation in different UKTI programmes, This includes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/passport-to-export-service"&gt;Passport to Export&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/gateway-to-global-growth"&gt;Gateway to Global Growth&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/overseas-market-introduction-service"&gt;Overseas Market Introduction Service&lt;/a&gt; (OMIS) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2 id="background"&gt;Background&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Warsash based &lt;a rel="external" href="http://www.polycast.co.uk"&gt;Polycast&lt;/a&gt; is famous for making the world’s most recognised car mascot, the ‘Spirit of Ecstasy’. This emblem is found on the front of Rolls Royce cars.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The 30 year old firm has seen big growth over the last 10 years, through its 50% joint venture ownership of Unipol Ltd. This has transformed the £2 million turnover company into a £25 million international company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The new factory will add to their 2 existing foundries in China, and their aerospace approved foundry in India. They will have 220,000 sq ft of production space in total across the 4 sites.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="contact-us"&gt;Contact us&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Book an appointment with an &lt;a rel="external" href="http://www.greatbusiness.gov.uk/ukti/?utm_source=UKTIHomepage&amp;amp;utm_medium=GOVUK&amp;amp;utm_campaign=EIG"&gt;export adviser&lt;/a&gt; if you’re interested in developing your business overseas.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:www.gov.uk,2005:AnnouncementPresenter/252086</id>
    <published>2014-07-29T09:39:49+01:00</published>
    <updated>2014-07-29T09:39:49+01:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/official-statistics-on-insolvencies-in-england-and-wales-for-the-period-april-to-june-2014"/>
    <title>News story: Official statistics on insolvencies in England and Wales for the period April to June 2014</title>
    <category label="News story" term="News story"/>
    <summary>Official statistics on insolvencies in England and Wales for the period April to June 2014 are published today (29 July 2014) by the Insolvency Service.
</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class="govspeak"&gt;&lt;p&gt;The number of company liquidations in England and Wales decreased compared with April to June 2013. Administrations, company voluntary arrangements and receiverships were also lower than a year ago.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The number of people who became insolvent in England and Wales increased compared with April to June 2013. This is because of an increase of one-fifth in the number of individual voluntary arrangements , while the number of bankruptcies and debt relief orders decreased.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Insolvency Service Deputy Chief Executive, Graham Horne said: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The Insolvency Service supports people and businesses in financial difficulty, while protecting the interests of creditors.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Today’s figures show that more people have become insolvent than last year. There are a number of ways to manage debts over time, and it is important that people who need help should seek early advice. The Government-backed Money Advice Service has information on available advice.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p class="last-child"&gt;More than half the people entering formal insolvency are now using individual voluntary arrangements (IVAs) to deal with their debts compared with other forms of personal insolvencies. Over the last year, there was a 20 percent increase in IVAs while bankruptcies and debt relief orders decreased. Company liquidations decreased over the last three months, reflecting a similar trend over the last year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/statistics/insolvency-statistics-april-to-june-2014"&gt;View the statistics release&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:www.gov.uk,2005:AnnouncementPresenter/252081</id>
    <published>2014-07-29T09:30:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2014-07-29T09:30:00+01:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/new-measures-to-tighten-up-the-immigration-system"/>
    <title>Press release: New measures to tighten up the immigration system</title>
    <category label="Press release" term="Press release"/>
    <summary>David Cameron and Theresa May have announced changes to universities and colleges seeking sponsor status and European migrants' benefits.</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class="govspeak"&gt;&lt;p&gt;A new crackdown on immigration abuses was announced today by the Prime Minister and the Home Secretary as part of the government’s long-term economic plan to secure a better future for Britain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From November, tougher rules will be imposed on universities and colleges who sponsor international students to study in the UK.  Currently, educational institutions cannot enjoy highly trusted sponsor status if 20% or more of the individuals they have offered places to are refused visas. But that figure will be cut to 10% in November after a 3 month transitional period for colleges and universities to re-examine their admissions procedures before offering individuals places.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Prime Minister also announced plans to halve the period over which European migrants can claim benefits. From November, European jobseekers will only be able to claim Jobseekers Allowance and other key welfare benefits for a maximum period of 3 months. This follows tough changes that were announced earlier this year to introduce a minimum 3 month delay to claiming benefits and to cut off benefits after 6 months unless the individual has very clear job prospects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class="call-to-action"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The government has also launched a &lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/consultations/recruitment-sector-prohibiting-the-advertising-of-jobs-exclusively-in-other-eea-countries"&gt;consultation on banning overseas-only advertising for jobs.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Prime Minister David Cameron said:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Hardworking people expect and deserve an immigration system that puts Britain first. Over the past 4 years we have clamped down on abuses, making sure the right people are coming here for the right reasons.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p class="last-child"&gt;At the same time, as part of our long-term economic plan, we have been fixing our education, training and welfare problems with radical school reform, record numbers of apprenticeships and an employment rate that has never been higher. All of these measures will ensure British people get a fair deal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;figure class="image embedded"&gt;&lt;div class="img"&gt;&lt;img alt="Immigration officers explain their roles to David Cameron and Theresa May." src="https://assets.digital.cabinet-office.gov.uk/government/uploads/system/uploads/image_data/file/29153/Immigration_govuk2.jpg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;The new restrictions were announced as the first measures of the government’s flagship &lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/collections/immigration-bill"&gt;Immigration Act 2014&lt;/a&gt; came into force, including:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;restrictions on the abuse of Article 8 of the European Convention on Human Rights – the right to family life – by migrants to avoid deportation; in the future, judges must consider the British public interest too&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;a new system of “deport now, appeal later” which will help the authorities to remove foreign criminals; if convicted criminals want to appeal against the decision, they will have to do so from their own country &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;new powers to revoke the driving licences of illegal immigrants – a total of 3,150 have been revoked since its introduction earlier this month&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;With almost 70,000 appeals heard every year, the new Immigration Act aims to cut the current level of Article 8 legislation abuses by making sure the right to family and private life is not regarded as absolute or undisputed. Section 19 of the Act puts into statute the principle that the law should be on the side of the British public and there is an expectation that the courts should have proper regard to Parliament’s view of what the public interest requires.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other measures in the Act will further limit the benefits and services migrants can access and make it easier to remove people with no legal right to be in the UK. It will also make the UK less attractive to people who want to come here to try to exploit the system. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Home Secretary Theresa May said:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;We are building an immigration system that is fair to British citizens and legitimate migrants, but tough on those who abuse it or flout the law.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;The Immigration Act is a landmark piece of legislation that will make Britain a less attractive place for those who come here for the wrong reasons, and allow us to remove more people when they have no right to remain.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;We will always act when we see abuse of our immigration system. And that is why we are tightening the rules to cut out abuse in the student visa system.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p class="last-child"&gt;These reforms are helping to deliver what we have always promised – to build an immigration system that truly works in the national interest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The government is also today launching a &lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/consultations/recruitment-sector-prohibiting-the-advertising-of-jobs-exclusively-in-other-eea-countries"&gt;consultation on banning overseas-only advertising&lt;/a&gt; – legally requiring employment agencies to advertise in Britain, and new plans to restrict the number of Job Centre Plus jobs which are automatically advertised on an EU-wide job portal.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="notes-to-editors"&gt;Notes to editors&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Since 1 January 2014 the government has introduced a number of new measures to limit access to benefits for EU nationals and we have introduced new powers to tackle fraud and abuse. These measures are expected to save the UK taxpayer £500 million over the next 5 years:
    &lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a new minimum 3 month delay before an EU jobseeker can claim benefits and a 6 month time-limit on Jobseekers Allowance unless the EU jobseeker can show they have clear prospects of an imminent job start&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;if the EU national claims to be in work or to have recently been working we’ll apply a new Minimum Earnings Threshold of £153 per week to help decide whether the work can be treated as meaningful and effective&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;since 1 April EU jobseekers are also no longer able to claim Housing Benefit&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;on 31 Dec 2013 DCLG issued new statutory guidance to make sure local authorities set a residency requirement for qualification for social housing&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;HMRC have introduced increased compliance checks in respect of child benefit and child tax credit payments to EEA nationals &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;on 1 July HMRC also introduced a similar 3 month delay before an economically inactive EU national can claim child benefit and child tax credit&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;there is also a stronger gateway test (the Habitual Residence Test) which all migrants must satisfy in order to access benefits &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;EU nationals who are removed from the UK for not exercising Treaty rights, for example for begging or rough sleeping, will be unable to re-enter the UK for 12 months (following removal) unless they have a valid reason to be here&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;For full details of Immigration Act measures commenced today visit:
    &lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a rel="external" href="http://www.legislation.gov.uk/uksi/2014/1820/contents/made"&gt;The Immigration Act 2014 (Commencement No. 1, Transitory and Saving Provisions) Order 2014&lt;/a&gt;   &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a rel="external" href="http://www.legislation.gov.uk/uksi/2014/1943/contents/made"&gt;The Immigration Act 2014 (Commencement No. 2) Order 2014&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
&lt;a rel="external" href="http://www.legislation.gov.uk/uksi/2014/1798/contents/made"&gt;The Immigration Act 2014 (Specified Anti-fraud Organisation) Order 2014&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:www.gov.uk,2005:AnnouncementPresenter/252072</id>
    <published>2014-07-28T19:14:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2014-07-28T19:14:00+01:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/joint-call-with-obama-merkel-hollande-and-renzi"/>
    <title>Press release: Joint call with Obama, Merkel, Hollande and Renzi</title>
    <category label="Press release" term="Press release"/>
    <summary>The Prime Minister spoke to President Obama, Chancellor Merkel, President Hollande and Prime Minister Renzi in a joint call this afternoon.</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class="govspeak"&gt;&lt;p&gt;A spokesperson said:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The Prime Minister spoke to President Obama, Chancellor Merkel, President Hollande and Prime Minister Renzi in a joint call this afternoon. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The discussion focussed on the international response to the MH17 disaster and Russia’s ongoing efforts to destabilise Ukraine. They agreed that the immediate priority must be to secure unrestricted access to the MH17 crash site, both to recover any remaining victims and to allow an unimpeded investigation of the site.  They noted their support for Dutch and Australian efforts to secure such access.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“On the broader conflict in Eastern Ukraine, they agreed that Russia has failed to take the steps necessary to de-escalate the crisis, such as ceasing support for the separatists; stopping the flow of weapons across the border; and using its influence to ensure the release of hostages. Indeed the latest information from the region suggests that even since MH17 was shot down, Russia continues to transfer weapons across the border and to provide practical support to the separatists. Leaders agreed that the international community should therefore impose further costs on Russia and specifically that Ambassadors from across the EU should agree a strong package of sectoral sanctions as swiftly as possible. They agreed that the EU and United States should continue to work together to exert pressure on Russia to change course and to engage in a political resolution to the crisis before more innocent lives are lost.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class="call-to-action"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Read more about the &lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/malaysia-airlines-flight-mh17-uk-government-response"&gt;UK government response&lt;/a&gt; to the Malaysia Airlines flight MH17 disaster.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The leaders also discussed the deteriorating situation in Israel and Gaza and agreed on the urgent need for a lasting ceasefire in Gaza and Israel, backing the efforts of the Egyptian government to achieve this. They noted that the fighting will not lead to lasting peace or security for either Israelis or Palestinians.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“They also touched on Libya given the worsening security situation and agreed that the United Nations has a vital role to play to facilitate the political process that could help to restore stability in the country. Finally, they discussed the situation in Iraq and progress towards establishing an inclusive government that represents all Iraqis.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:www.gov.uk,2005:AnnouncementPresenter/252065</id>
    <published>2014-07-28T17:20:05+01:00</published>
    <updated>2014-07-28T17:20:05+01:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/strategic-planning-and-transactions-conference"/>
    <title>News story: Strategic planning and transactions conference</title>
    <category label="News story" term="News story"/>
    <summary>A development event for chairs and chief executives of NHS foundation trusts and NHS trusts</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class="govspeak"&gt;&lt;h4 id="central-london-thursday-16-october-2014"&gt;Central London, Thursday 16 October 2014&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Monitor, the NHS Trust Development Authority and the Foundation Trust Network are offering a 1 day, interactive event at no cost. This is in response to feedback from chairs and chief executives who said that leading change in local health economies, strategic planning and competition rules and processes are 3 priority areas where development opportunities and further information would be helpful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The day will be a chance to hear from foundation trusts on their experience of developing and testing a new strategic planning toolkit currently under development. It will also give delegates an opportunity to increase their knowledge and understanding of:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the link between effective board governance and strategic planning&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;learning and good practice identified by Monitor and TDA in the 2-year and 5-year plans submitted in 2014/15, including common themes of where trusts have struggled to meet plans in the past&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;the introduction of a new strategic planning toolkit &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;how the new competition rules and regulations will operate, in particular the process between Monitor and the CMA&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;good practice in preparing a case for a merger, acquisition or significant transaction&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Chairs and chief executives will hear from other trusts on these areas including how they have addressed planning within their local health economies and learnings from going through merger and significant transaction processes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whilst there will be sharing from Monitor and the TDA, this is very much a development event and there will be lots of opportunity to hear from, and question, your peers on their experiences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The event is for chairs and chief executives of NHS foundation trusts and NHS trusts only. Space is limited so please do not register for the event if you are not one of the above.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There will be a further opportunity at the end of the day to discuss or question Monitor or TDA informally about specific issues relating to strategic planning, competition rules and transaction processes which are relevant to your own circumstances. Please let us know during the registration process if you would like to take advantage of this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about the event please contact Helen Crumley at Monitor: helen.crumley@monitor.gov.uk or on 0203 747 0532.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:www.gov.uk,2005:AnnouncementPresenter/252057</id>
    <published>2014-07-28T16:35:53+01:00</published>
    <updated>2014-07-28T16:35:53+01:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/how-to-train-your-family"/>
    <title>News story: 'How to train your family'</title>
    <category label="News story" term="News story"/>
    <summary>Fire Services Minister Penny Mordaunt welcomes unique collaboration between award-winning Fire Kills campaign and DreamWorks’ 'How to train your dragon 2'</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class="govspeak"&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Department for Communities and Local Government has teamed up with the Hollywood animation studio, DreamWorks, to launch an innovative partnership between the award-winning &lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/firekills"&gt;Fire Kills campaign&lt;/a&gt; and the new ‘How to train your dragon 2’ movie.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fire Kills encourages families to test their smoke alarms on the first day of every month, using a wide range of media channels to target audiences of all ages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The collaboration is an example of how the government is working constructively with the private sector to the benefit of both partners.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The plot of the DreamWorks production released through 20th Century Fox - with friendly fire-breathing dragons living in wooden Viking homes, with obvious home fire risks - presented an opportunity for collaboration, using the power of the film’s brand to reach families and improve public safety. Producers permitted the use of selected images and characters from the film and arranged for special artwork to be commissioned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fire Kills then ran a special ‘How to train your family’ campaign in the week leading up to the film’s launch on 11 July, benefiting from the extensive wider promotion of the film and targeting families with young children who, hopefully, will pester their parents to test their smoke alarms regularly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The collaboration resulted in an eye-catching press advert using images of the main characters Hiccup and Toothless - the dragon blowing smoke towards the smoke alarm and a call to action ‘test your smoke alarm on the first of every month’.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fire Kills launched the advert in the week of the film release through a Featurelink campaign – with editorial copy running alongside a paid for advert – in local newspapers across England, tailored in many areas by the inclusion of local fire and rescue service contact details. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a rel="external" href="https://www.facebook.com/firekills"&gt;Fire Kills Facebook page&lt;/a&gt; - with a following of 26,000 - also posted a modified version of the advert and promoted the message: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p class="last-child"&gt;You may not have a fire-breathing dragon in your home but you still need to train your family to test your smoke alarms to keep them safe. If you forgot on the first of the month, do it today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This post, uploaded on 8 July reached well over 1 million people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Fire Kills team at the department and at Dorset Fire and Rescue Service also worked to develop content for an education pack which DreamWorks illustrated with their dragon characters - a valuable resource available to all fire and rescue services to use as part of outreach work with schools and young people. A special screening of the film took place in Dorset for the main partner school as a thank you for their support.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fire Services Minister Penny Mordaunt said:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The Fire Kills campaign’s collaboration with ‘How to train your dragon 2’ is a brilliant way to spread this life-saving public safety message and reach a wider audience through partnership.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;The plot of the film and familiarity of its characters was too good an opportunity to miss given our campaign objective of persuading families to be more fire safe by regularly testing their smoke alarms.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p class="last-child"&gt;The power of young people’s influence is well known as being effective in getting parents to change their behaviour. And ‘How to train your family’ was the perfect way to tie the 2 together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id="further-information"&gt;Further information&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fire Kills is run by the Department for Communities and Local Government in partnership with England’s 46 fire and rescue authorities. Its main aim is to encourage householders to make sure their smoke alarms are working by testing them regularly. The campaign also promotes other home &lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/collections/fire-safety-guidance"&gt;fire safety&lt;/a&gt; messages, including planning escape routes, careful disposal of smoking products, taking extra care with cooking and electrical devices, installing extra smoke alarms where there are risks and testing for other people who need help. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main ‘Tick. Tock. Test’ campaign over the 2 clock change weekends in October and March urges people to test their smoke alarms when they change their clocks to check they are working properly. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2013, the Fire Kills campaign’s successes included:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Marketing Society Award for Excellence (Not for Profit category) &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Account Planning Group Silver Award &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Millward Brown Award for Best Insight &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Campaign magazine top 10 regional newspaper adverts for 2013&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:www.gov.uk,2005:AnnouncementPresenter/252050</id>
    <published>2014-07-28T16:27:13+01:00</published>
    <updated>2014-07-28T16:27:13+01:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/hints-of-features"/>
    <title>News story: Hints of features</title>
    <category label="News story" term="News story"/>
    <summary>In the latest Rosetta images, taken from a distance of 5500 km from comet 67P, large features are beginning to stand out.</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class="govspeak"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Each image in this sequence is separated by two hours, and the comet rotates with a period of approximately 12.4 hours. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The change in position of the dark strip across the ‘neck’ of the comet in the second and third images is a result of the change in illumination and the resulting shadows cast on the surface as the comet rotates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One area of the neck seems significantly brighter than surrounding regions. This bright region, seen most clearly in the first image, may result from differences in surface composition or grain size. For example, could it be a region of freshly exposed ice or the product of resurfacing. Alternatively, it could be a topographical effect. The cause of this bright region will become clearer once higher-resolution images and spectral data are available.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The comet’s neck (the join between the two segments of the comet nucleus) will hold important clues to the comet’s evolution history. Studying this region from close up, not just with images but also with other instruments to assess its composition, will help determine if the comet is a result of two separate bodies that are fused together, or if it is one object that has eroded in a dramatic fashion to produce the shape we see.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other features are also becoming apparent, although caution must still be exercised before drawing any robust scientific conclusions. But there is more reason this week to speculate that there might be a large depression – maybe an impact crater – on the smaller lobe of the comet (towards the bottom in the first image in the sequence). The images have a resolution of 100 metres per pixel, implying that this feature could be several hundred metres across. If it does indeed turn out to be an impact crater then its large size – along with composition information collected later – will help teach us about the comet’s interior properties, perhaps offering information on its strength and porosity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Several other dark features seen on the body of the comet may also be shadows due to depressions, although at this distance it is not yet possible to conclude whether they are impact craters or the result, for example, of localised collapse caused by a weaker subsurface layer giving way – or something else completely!
Even though it is still difficult to discern individual features, it is possible to assess the comet’s shape. Indeed, from the images taken on 14 July, the OSIRIS team has begun modelling the comet’s three-dimensional shape. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cadence at which OSIRIS is making observations of the comet is now increasing, focusing on different aspects of cometary science, and not just on the details of the nucleus. In general, some observations will focus on basic parameters of the comet, such as rotation rate and shape, and determining its mass and volume in order to establish its density, while others will provide wider-angle views of comet’s environment. Similarly, Rosetta’s other science instruments are also beginning to analyse the comet at a range of wavelengths to determine the comet’s temperature, gas and dust composition and production rates, nucleus composition and more. By 6 August, we expect to see high-resolution, close-up views of the comet surface.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="rosetta-and-the-uk"&gt;Rosetta and the UK&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rosetta is a mission with significant UK involvement from industry and science.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the main challenges for all the companies designing instruments for Rosetta has been to ensure the components remain intact for ten years, while the spacecraft makes its way to the comet, and then work perfectly when it gets there. Not an easy task!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More about UK involvement in the mission can be found on our &lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/case-studies/rosetta"&gt;Rosetta page.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:www.gov.uk,2005:AnnouncementPresenter/251985</id>
    <published>2014-07-28T16:25:28+01:00</published>
    <updated>2014-07-28T16:25:28+01:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/dave-barnes"/>
    <title>News story: Dave Barnes</title>
    <category label="News story" term="News story"/>
    <summary>It was with great sadness that we learnt of the death of Prof. Dave Barnes, Head of Space Robotics at Aberystwyth University on 25 July.</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class="govspeak"&gt;&lt;p&gt;He was a central figure in the UK’s Mars exploration programme over a number of years and instrumental in taking forward the UK ambitions in space robotics. He was responsible for the Beagle 2 Lander robot arm calibration, software modelling, simulation, and visualization and took this expertise into the European Mars Rover mission, ExoMars. Here Dave was a Co-Investigator on the Panoramic Camera (PanCam) science instrument, working on modelling, simulation, image data processing and science data visualisation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to his acknowledged scientific expertise, Dave played a key role in developing the UK’s strategy for involvement in Mars, being on the Aurora Advisory Committee from 2005 until 2012. Importantly he ensured that the UK space programme benefitted from advances in computer sciences and conversely fed back space research into applications on Earth.  Dave was also a founding member of the UK Space and Planetary Robotics Network and was a member of the UK STFC Particle Physics, Astronomy and Nuclear Physics Science Committee (PPAN). His boundless enthusiasm and bubbly personality will be sorely missed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:www.gov.uk,2005:AnnouncementPresenter/244991</id>
    <published>2014-07-01T16:11:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2014-07-28T16:21:04+01:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/points-of-light-july-2014-winners"/>
    <title>News story: Points of Light: July 2014 winners</title>
    <category label="News story" term="News story"/>
    <summary>The Points of Light award recognises outstanding individuals - people who are making a change in their community and inspiring others.</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Updated:&lt;/em&gt; Added recipient number 73 - Sue Ransley.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="govspeak"&gt;&lt;p&gt;The following people were given a Points of Light award in July 2014 (the numbering continues from &lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/points-of-light-june-2014-winners"&gt;June’s winners&lt;/a&gt;):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="christine-howard-surrey"&gt;54. Christine Howard (Surrey)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Christine wins the award for helping set up both the Surrey Hills Society and the not-for-profit Surrey Hills Enterprises Community Interest Company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="jennie-williams-merseyside"&gt;55. Jennie Williams (Merseyside)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jennie wins the award for working to improve the diets of many people in her community through &lt;a rel="external" href="http://shoots-food.co.uk/"&gt;‘Shoots’.&lt;/a&gt; Jennie also helps run the local residents association and volunteers with a local youth project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="mel-woodards-somerset"&gt;56. Mel Woodards (Somerset)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mel has used her love of football to create sporting opportunities for hundreds of young people in Somerset. She decided to set up a league for younger players between 6 and 10 years old. Originally aiming to attract 100 to 200 young players to the league, Mel has now recruited her 900th player.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="maxine-green-leeds"&gt;57. Maxine Green (Leeds)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maxine wins the award for giving over 9,000 volunteering hours on a wide range of projects. In 2013 alone she raised over £700,000 for local causes. Most recently Maxine was selected as a volunteer for the 2014 &lt;a rel="external" href="http://letour.yorkshire.com/"&gt;Tour de France Grand Départ&lt;/a&gt; in Yorkshire.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="alison-grant-london"&gt;58. Alison Grant (London)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alison wins the award for helping create the largest under-16 cycling club in the country. Alison joined the &lt;a rel="external" href="http://www.slipstreamers.co.uk/hillingdonslipstreamers/"&gt;Slipstreamers Club&lt;/a&gt; 14 years ago; the Slipstreamers Go-Ride Club now has over 300 members compared to the 20 at its start in 1998.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="jake-hayman-london"&gt;59. Jake Hayman (London)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wanting to give something back to his old school, Jake organised a group of his former schoolmates to go back and provide relatable careers advice to current students. Following the event’s success Jake set up &lt;a rel="external" href="http://futurefirst.org.uk/"&gt;Future First&lt;/a&gt; to build networks of former students to do the same in other state schools.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="yvonne-jarvis-birmingham"&gt;60. Yvonne Jarvis (Birmingham)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yvonne wins the award for using her own life savings to set up the Brooke House Project in Erdington, Birmingham. Run entirely by volunteers, the Christian charity reaches out to marginalised people in the community who have dependency and behavioural issues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="tom-moore-norfolk"&gt;61. Tom Moore (Norfolk)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tom wins the award for volunteering with his local Air Ambulance: he has flown more than 500 missions for the East Anglian Air Ambulance service.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="pete-smart-wiltshire"&gt;62. Pete Smart (Wiltshire)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Volunteer groundsman and coach Pete wins the award for his work in youth football. As well as painting over 5,000 miles of lines for football pitches, he’s now training the grandchildren of people he coached when he was younger.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="jackie-patton-county-down"&gt;63. Jackie Patton (County Down)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jackie becomes the first person in Northern Ireland to win the award; her volunteering efforts brought a major world championship event to her local sailing club. Jackie coordinated a network of 60 volunteers, helping the club to expand and host events, including the prestigious Formula 18 Catamaran World Sailing Championships.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="jess-starns-berkshire"&gt;64. Jess Starns (Berkshire)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jess wins the award for setting up &lt;a rel="external" href="http://dyspraxic.me.uk/"&gt;Dyspraxic Me&lt;/a&gt;. Inspired by her personal experience of living with dyspraxia, Jess also organises speakers, trainers and guests for Dyspraxic Me events, helping many young people with dyspraxia improve their personal and work skills.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="dave-brook-leeds"&gt;65. Dave Brook (Leeds)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dave wins the award for setting up his own gang resistance programme, ‘Karate for Inner City Kids’ (KICK) to help young people develop a healthier lifestyle away from the influence of crime and drugs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="ron-andrew-manchester"&gt;66. Ron Andrew (Manchester)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ron wins the award for tending the graves of local soldiers who fought in the First or Second World War. Ron, a former drum major, spends his time and his own money cleaning headstones and buying flowers and urns to make sure those who gave so much are not forgotten.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="frank-blades-lincolnshire"&gt;67. Frank Blades (Lincolnshire)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After his wife was discharged from hospital Frank became her carer, but felt that they had been sent home without adequate support or advice. Frank wins the award for campaigning about issues that carers face; his work led to all the Lincolnshire Healthcare Trust hospitals introducing a new Carers Policy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="jean-wilson-worcester"&gt;68. Jean Wilson (Worcester)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jean wins the award for founding the charity &lt;a rel="external" href="http://www.newhopeworcester.co.uk/index.aspx?redirect=true&amp;amp;infoid=1"&gt;New Hope.&lt;/a&gt; New Hope supports the families of local children who have disabilities and complex health care needs. Jean founded the group in 2010 when she discovered that there was little support in her area for her daughter Emily, who was diagnosed with a severe disability at 17 months old.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="yvonne-obura-salisbury"&gt;69. Yvonne Obura (Salisbury)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yvonne wins the award for raising awareness of Female Genital Mutilation (&lt;abbr title="Female Genital Mutilation"&gt;FGM&lt;/abbr&gt;) amongst UK doctors. Realising that their knowledge of &lt;abbr title="Female Genital Mutilation"&gt;FGM&lt;/abbr&gt; was low, she volunteered through the charity Orchid Project, helping to develop training materials and guidance for doctors on how to approach cases of &lt;abbr title="Female Genital Mutilation"&gt;FGM&lt;/abbr&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="lauren-eaves-st-albans"&gt;70. Lauren Eaves (St Albans)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lauren wins the award for her campaigning against child marriage. Lauren volunteers as a youth advisor and ambassador for &lt;a rel="external" href="http://www.plan-uk.org/"&gt;Plan UK,&lt;/a&gt; a charity that works with the world’s poorest children so they can move themselves from a life of poverty to a future with opportunity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="jenny-thomson-aberdeen"&gt;71. Jenny Thomson (Aberdeen)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jenny wins the award for her volunteering work at both the 1970 Commonwealth Games in Edinburgh and now the 2014 games in Glasgow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="jackie-murphy-london"&gt;72. Jackie Murphy (London)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pearly Queen Jackie has carried on the traditions of her ancestors – who were first crowned Pearly Kings and Queens in 1894 – by raising thousands of pounds for charity. Recently she helped raise £65,000 so that primary school students from a local special needs school will have access to a swimming pool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="sue-ransley-west-sussex"&gt;73. Sue Ransley (West Sussex)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sue led the way in a large community effort that saw her village get a new local store. With a troop of volunteers, Sue raised almost £250,000 to buy a building in the village and then transformed it into an attractive shop premises.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:www.gov.uk,2005:AnnouncementPresenter/252035</id>
    <published>2014-07-28T16:15:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2014-07-28T16:15:00+01:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/nato-exercise-to-reassure-allies"/>
    <title>News story: NATO exercise to reassure allies</title>
    <category label="News story" term="News story"/>
    <summary>UK commits to major military exercise in Poland to support eastern European allies.</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class="govspeak"&gt;&lt;p&gt;The UK will send a battle group to take part in major military training, Exercise Black Eagle, in October as part of a NATO package to reassure allies in eastern Europe. The full battle group will comprise of 1,350 personnel and more than 350 armoured and other vehicles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Defence Secretary Michael Fallon made the announcement today during a visit to Warsaw with Foreign Secretary Philip Hammond.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This new commitment is Britain’s largest to the region since 2008 and is one of a planned series of NATO manoeuvres due to take place throughout the autumn in support of allies in Eastern Europe and the Baltic states.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As part of a sustained commitment since Russia’s illegal annexation of Crimea, the UK has deployed RAF Typhoon jets to the NATO Baltic Air Policing mission, as well as participating in smaller scale army exercises across Europe. At the end of August light infantry troops from &lt;a rel="external" href="http://www.army.mod.uk/infantry/regiments/29497.aspx"&gt;1st Battalion, The Duke of Lancaster’s Regiment&lt;/a&gt; will take part in Exercise Sabre Junction, a US-led exercise involving 16 &lt;a rel="external" href="http://www.nato.int/"&gt;NATO&lt;/a&gt; and partner nations which is also taking place in Poland. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Defence Secretary said: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p class="last-child"&gt;It is right that NATO members and partners demonstrate our commitment to the collective security of our allies in Eastern Europe, so I am pleased to confirm our participation in these exercises. In particular, the commitment of a battle group to Exercise Black Eagle shows our sustained and substantial support to NATO’s eastern border.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the 4-5 September this year NATO will hold a summit in Wales. The event will be a central platform for member nations to discuss how to equip the alliance to respond to future threats and agree more reassurance measures. The summit will be one of the most important in NATO’s history, coming at a significant moment for the Alliance as the combat mission in Afghanistan draws to a close and, as events in Ukraine and Iraq have shown, the world faces more complex threats than ever before. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mr Fallon added: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p class="last-child"&gt;We have a strong opportunity at the NATO summit to discuss how we will continue our response to Russia’s illegal annexation of Crimea and its destabilisation of eastern Ukraine. The UK is playing a central role and we are not ruling out further enhancements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:www.gov.uk,2005:AnnouncementPresenter/252053</id>
    <published>2014-07-28T16:07:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2014-07-28T16:07:00+01:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/foreign-secretary-sends-eid-al-fitr-message"/>
    <title>News story: Foreign Secretary sends Eid al-Fitr message</title>
    <category label="News story" term="News story"/>
    <summary>Foreign Secretary sends his best wishes to Muslims celebrating Eid across the world.</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class="govspeak"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Foreign Secretary Philip Hammond said:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The Islamic festival of Eid al-Fitr marks a time of celebration and coming together by Muslims around the world.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;This is a special time for millions of people of all nationalities and backgrounds, highlighting the diversity and reach of Islam as a global religion.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;I would like to send my warmest wishes to Muslims in Britain and across the world as they and their families celebrate this holy festival.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;At this time we must also offer our thoughts and prayers to civilians who are caught up in conflicts, particularly in Gaza, Syria, and Iraq.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p class="last-child"&gt;With these reflections I wish you all a blessed and peaceful Eid Mubarak.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id="further-information"&gt;Further information&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Follow the Foreign Office on twitter &lt;a rel="external" href="https://twitter.com/foreignoffice"&gt;@foreignoffice&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Follow the Foreign Office on &lt;a rel="external" href="https://www.facebook.com/foreignoffice?ref=hl"&gt;facebook&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a rel="external" href="https://plus.google.com/b/105922144104190309938/+foreignoffice/posts"&gt;Google+&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class="contact" id="contact_193"&gt;
  &lt;div class="content"&gt;
    &lt;h3&gt;Media enquiries&lt;/h3&gt;

    &lt;div class="vcard contact-inner"&gt;

        &lt;div class="email-url-number"&gt;
            &lt;p class="email"&gt;
              &lt;span class="type"&gt;Email&lt;/span&gt;
              &lt;a class="email" href="mailto:newsdesk@fco.gov.uk"&gt;newsdesk@fco.gov.uk&lt;/a&gt;
            &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p class="tel"&gt;
              &lt;span class="type"&gt;News Desk &lt;/span&gt;
              020 7008 3100
            &lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;


    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:www.gov.uk,2005:AnnouncementPresenter/252039</id>
    <published>2014-07-28T15:39:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2014-07-28T15:39:00+01:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/child-flu-vaccine-pilots-announced-for-second-year"/>
    <title>Press release: Child flu vaccine pilots announced for second year</title>
    <category label="Press release" term="Press release"/>
    <summary>Child flu vaccine pilots enter their second year, and a new set of locations have been announced.    </summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class="govspeak"&gt;&lt;p&gt;More than 700,000 healthy school-aged children across England are to be offered a free flu vaccination for the winter, as the successful child flu vaccine pilot programme launched in 2013 by Public Health England (&lt;abbr title="Public Health England"&gt;PHE&lt;/abbr&gt;) enters the second year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2013 to 2014 vaccinations were offered to primary school-aged children in a cross-section of urban, rural and inner city settings. New for this year, there will also be further pilots for children in years 7 and 8 (aged around 11 to 13 years) in selected secondary schools around the country. Most children who will be offered the vaccine in pilot areas will be given it as a nasal spray. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to protecting healthy children from flu, the pilots aim to reduce the spread of flu and protect younger siblings, grandparents and others who are at increased risk of becoming seriously ill from flu. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Department of Health (&lt;abbr title="Department of Health"&gt;DH&lt;/abbr&gt;), based on a recommendation received from the Joint Committee on Vaccination and Immunisation (&lt;abbr title="Joint Committee on Vaccination and Immunisation"&gt;JCVI&lt;/abbr&gt;) in July 2012, decided to extend the national flu programme to all children from the age of 2 to less than 17 years. This extension is being phased in, and the pilots are determining the best approach to implementing the programme for school-aged children, so that the programme can be implemented efficiently and sustainably, without putting pressure on other essential services.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This autumn, all children aged 2, 3 and 4 will also be offered a nasal spray vaccine to protect them against flu. This accompanies the existing flu programme, which provides flu vaccination to anyone in an at risk group, pregnant women and those aged 65 or over.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dr Paul Cosford, Director for Health Protection and Medical Director at &lt;abbr title="Public Health England"&gt;PHE&lt;/abbr&gt;, said:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The pilots are an important addition to the national programme and are being carefully planned for the second year running. They are helping us to understand the best way to implement the programme nationally, ensuring that we can set up a successful and sustainable programme, vaccinating children and young people to protect them and the wider population.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p class="last-child"&gt;It’s important that children take up the offer of a vaccination if offered to them later in the year. Every year, 100s of 1000s of people may see their &lt;abbr title="General practitioner (family doctor)"&gt;GP&lt;/abbr&gt; and 10s of 1000s may be hospitalised because of flu each winter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dr Mary Ramsay, &lt;abbr title="Public Health England"&gt;PHE&lt;/abbr&gt;’s head of immunisation said:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Last year there was an overall uptake of 52.5% in school-age children and early findings from the pilots suggest a likely impact of vaccinating on levels of flu circulating more widely.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p class="last-child"&gt;The high uptake levels achieved in most pilot areas last year using school-based delivery demonstrate the feasibility of achieving high coverage levels and this is encouraging as we approach the second year of the pilots. However, it is important that we continue this on-going close monitoring of the programme.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the specific pilot areas where vaccination is to be offered to school-age children, local NHS screening and immunisation teams are now in the process of making arrangements to ensure they can offer the vaccinations in the autumn. Details of how the pilots will be delivered locally in these areas will be available later in the year. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An NHS England spokesperson said: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p class="last-child"&gt;NHS England will continue to commission and ensure the delivery of the national flu programme across England.  The fact that it’s been extended to children and young people via the Healthy Schools Programme is a positive, benefitting both children and their families.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id="ends"&gt;Ends&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h2 id="notes-to-editors"&gt;Notes to editors&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In 2014 to 2015, pilots will be carried out in parts of the following areas:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Pilot Area 2014 to 2015&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;School Cohort&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Cumbria, Northumberland, Tyne and Wear&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Primary&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Greater Manchester&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Primary and secondary&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Lancashire&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Secondary&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;North Yorkshire and Humber&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Secondary&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Sheffield, Rotherham, Doncaster and Bassetlaw&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Secondary&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;West Yorkshire&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Secondary&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Arden, Herefordshire and Worcestershire&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Secondary&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Birmingham, Solihull and The Black Country&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Secondary&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;East Anglia&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Secondary&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Essex&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Primary and secondary&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Leicestershire and Lincolnshire&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Primary and secondary&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Shropshire and Staffordshire&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Secondary&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;London&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Primary and secondary (year 7) in parts of London. All children in special schools across London.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The seasonal flu vaccination programme is based on independent expert advice from the Joint Committee on Vaccination and Immunisation (&lt;abbr title="Joint Committee on Vaccination and Immunisation"&gt;JCVI&lt;/abbr&gt;). The aim of the current flu vaccination policy is to reduce the serious morbidity and mortality due to flu by immunising those people most at risk of serious illness or death should they develop flu. This is in line with most other countries that have seasonal influenza vaccination programmes.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Pilots were designed to test which delivery method is the most efficient and is well-accepted by parents and children, and not to test the vaccine which has a long track record in the US. Posters highlighting &lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/uploads/system/uploads/attachment_data/file/309021/phe-who-gets-which-vaccine-05b_final.pdf"&gt;‘Which flu vaccine should you or your child have’&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/uploads/system/uploads/attachment_data/file/229912/DoH_8502_5_reasons_Flu_poster_06_accessible.pdf"&gt;‘5 reasons to get  your child vaccinated against flu’&lt;/a&gt; are available online&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/uploads/system/uploads/attachment_data/file/330282/PHE_8879_Flu_2014_DL_10_.pdf"&gt;new child flu leaflet&lt;/a&gt; is now available online. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;abbr title="Public Health England"&gt;PHE&lt;/abbr&gt; exists to protect and improve the nation’s health and wellbeing, and reduce health inequalities. It does this through advocacy, partnerships, world-class science, knowledge and intelligence, and the delivery of specialist public health services. &lt;abbr title="Public Health England"&gt;PHE&lt;/abbr&gt; is an operationally autonomous executive agency of the Department of Health. &lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/organisations/public-health-england"&gt;www.gov.uk/phe&lt;/a&gt; Follow us on Twitter @PHE_uk&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;div class="contact" id="contact_1905"&gt;
  &lt;div class="content"&gt;
    &lt;h3&gt;Public Health England&lt;/h3&gt;

    &lt;div class="vcard contact-inner"&gt;

        &lt;div class="email-url-number"&gt;
            &lt;p class="tel"&gt;
              &lt;span class="type"&gt;61 Colindale Avenue, London, NW9 5EQ&lt;/span&gt;
              Telephone: 020 8327 7901 Out of hours: 0208 200 4400
            &lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;


    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:www.gov.uk,2005:AnnouncementPresenter/252014</id>
    <published>2014-07-28T15:33:19+01:00</published>
    <updated>2014-07-28T15:33:19+01:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/foreign-secretary-welcomes-japans-command-of-counter-piracy"/>
    <title>Press release: Foreign Secretary welcomes Japan’s command of counter-piracy</title>
    <category label="Press release" term="Press release"/>
    <summary>Japan has announced it will take command of an anti-piracy operation in the Northern Indian Ocean and the Gulf of Aden.</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class="govspeak"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Combined Task Force 151 (CTF-151) is one of three operated by Combined Maritime Forces. Command is voluntary and rotated between the thirty member nations, with ships from participating navies escorting merchant vessels, responding to incidents of piracy and helping to ensure freedom of navigation. The task force also allows the member navies to cooperate better and so improve how they work together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Foreign Secretary Philip Hammond said:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I welcome a greater Japanese role in international peace and security.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Japan is already contributing to CTF-151.  Assuming command of combined efforts to combat piracy is a natural next step, which should be commended alongside Japan’s Seven Partners initiative on capacity building with ASEAN nations and reform to the legal basis for security.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p class="last-child"&gt;Tackling piracy is an issue for all nations, and crimes committed on the high seas off the coast of Somalia have a direct impact on the UK’s security.  I look forward to further joint activity between Japan and the United Kingdom in this area.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id="further-information"&gt;Further information&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Follow the Foreign Office on twitter &lt;a rel="external" href="https://twitter.com/foreignoffice"&gt;@foreignoffice&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Follow the Foreign Office on &lt;a rel="external" href="https://www.facebook.com/foreignoffice?ref=hl"&gt;facebook&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a rel="external" href="https://plus.google.com/b/105922144104190309938/+foreignoffice/posts"&gt;Google+&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class="contact" id="contact_193"&gt;
  &lt;div class="content"&gt;
    &lt;h3&gt;Media enquiries&lt;/h3&gt;

    &lt;div class="vcard contact-inner"&gt;

        &lt;div class="email-url-number"&gt;
            &lt;p class="email"&gt;
              &lt;span class="type"&gt;Email&lt;/span&gt;
              &lt;a class="email" href="mailto:newsdesk@fco.gov.uk"&gt;newsdesk@fco.gov.uk&lt;/a&gt;
            &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p class="tel"&gt;
              &lt;span class="type"&gt;News Desk &lt;/span&gt;
              020 7008 3100
            &lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;


    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:www.gov.uk,2005:AnnouncementPresenter/252034</id>
    <published>2014-07-28T15:08:37+01:00</published>
    <updated>2014-07-28T15:08:37+01:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.gov.uk/government/speeches/planning-for-unconventional-oil-and-gas"/>
    <title>Statement to Parliament: Planning for unconventional oil and gas</title>
    <category label="Statement to Parliament" term="Statement to Parliament"/>
    <summary>Written ministerial statement by Lord Ahmad of Wimbledon on planning for unconventional oil and gas.</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class="govspeak"&gt;&lt;p&gt;This Coalition government believes that shale gas has the potential to provide the UK with greater energy security, growth and jobs. Effective exploration and testing of the UK’s unconventional gas resources is key to understanding the potential for this industry so the government is creating the right framework to accelerate unconventional oil and gas development in a responsible and sustainable way. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That is why this Coalition government has put in place an effective planning system to support unconventional oil and gas production in this country. We have amended regulations to streamline notification requirements and the calculation of fees to speed up the determination of planning applications, whilst ensuring the public are properly informed of planning applications in their locality. We have also updated planning guidance on oil and gas development to provide clarity on the role of the planning system and we have introduced a streamlined common application form to ensure less onerous requirements on the industry. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other regulators, including the Department of Energy and Climate Change, the Environment Agency and the Health and Safety Executive will address sub-surface issues to protect against seismic disturbance or pollution of groundwater. Close working between all regulatory bodies will ensure that there remains a robust, comprehensive and safe regulatory regime in place.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To further the exploration and testing of our unconventional gas resources, the Department of Energy and Climate Change is today (28 July 2014) inviting applications for new onshore licences in the area defined in the Strategic Environmental Assessment which has been conducted for further onshore licensing. More details are outlined in today’s &lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/speeches/outcome-of-the-strategic-environmental-assessment"&gt;written ministerial statement by Baroness Verma&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is important to note that this Coalition government recognises there are areas of outstanding landscape and scenic beauty where the environmental and heritage qualities need to be carefully balanced against the benefits of oil and gas from unconventional hydrocarbons. For this reason, my department is today making clear our approach to planning for unconventional hydrocarbons in National Parks, the Broads, Areas of Outstanding Natural Beauty and World Heritage Sites, by providing some additional planning guidance. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Proposals for such development must recognise the importance of these sites. The guidance is available on the &lt;a rel="external" href="http://planningguidance.planningportal.gov.uk/blog/guidance/minerals/planning-for-hydrocarbon-extraction/determining-the-planning-application/#paragraph_223"&gt;minerals section&lt;/a&gt; of the government’s &lt;a rel="external" href="http://planningguidance.planningportal.gov.uk/"&gt;planning guidance website&lt;/a&gt; and a copy of the new section has been placed in the Library of the House.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We want to ensure that the government’s intentions in respect to development concerning unconventional hydrocarbons in these areas are given appropriate effect. So for the next 12 months from today, in applying the Secretary of State’s policy on recovering planning appeals (as stated in &lt;a rel="external" href="http://www.publications.parliament.uk/pa/cm200708/cmhansrd/cm080630/wmstext/80630m0001.htm"&gt;30 June 2008, Official Report, House of Commons, Column 43WS&lt;/a&gt;), my department will give particular attention to recovering appeals for such developments. The position on the recovery of appeals will be reviewed after 12 months.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:www.gov.uk,2005:AnnouncementPresenter/251992</id>
    <published>2014-07-28T14:18:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2014-07-28T14:18:00+01:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/dragons-den-investor-piers-linney-joins-cabinet-office-sme-panel"/>
    <title>News story: Dragons’ Den investor Piers Linney joins Cabinet Office SME Panel</title>
    <category label="News story" term="News story"/>
    <summary>Piers Linney, co-CEO of Outsourcery plc, has joined the Cabinet Office SME Panel, which advises on small and medium business issues.</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class="govspeak"&gt;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;abbr title="small and medium enterprise"&gt;SME&lt;/abbr&gt; Panel, formed in 2011, advises the Cabinet Office on work to help more small and medium enterprises (&lt;abbr title="small and medium enterprises"&gt;SMEs&lt;/abbr&gt;) to win public sector contracts and other &lt;abbr title="small and medium enterprise"&gt;SME&lt;/abbr&gt;-related issues. The panel consists of a broad range of micro, small and medium business leaders across a number of industry sectors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Piers Linney, co-Chief Executive Officer of cloud service provider Outsourcery plc, is also currently a panel member on BBC’s Dragons’ Den. He will provide further insight on the view from the IT sector. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On his appointment to the board, Piers Linney said:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The public sector provides a massive opportunity for &lt;abbr title="small and medium enterprises"&gt;SMEs&lt;/abbr&gt;, which are the engine of the economy. The aim of having &lt;abbr title="small and medium enterprises"&gt;SMEs&lt;/abbr&gt; account for 25% of direct and indirect central government expenditure is within reach and the &lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/how-to-use-cloudstore"&gt;G-Cloud framework&lt;/a&gt; in particular is a world leading example of how IT procurement should evolve to drive value for money and broaden supply bases to introduce more competition and innovation.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p class="last-child"&gt;However, it is important that such initiatives continue to adapt and that feedback is heard and acted upon and I look forward to adding our perspective.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stephen Allott, the Crown Representative for &lt;abbr title="small and medium enterprises"&gt;SMEs&lt;/abbr&gt; said:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The &lt;abbr title="small and medium enterprise"&gt;SME&lt;/abbr&gt; panel has been doing a fine job in acting as a sounding board for Cabinet Office policies and offering excellent advice at how best to make it easier for smaller firms to pitch for and win government business. Piers will offer the board further experience from the IT sector and we look forward to his input.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p class="last-child"&gt;Government is now getting huge value from &lt;abbr title="small and medium enterprise"&gt;SME&lt;/abbr&gt; IT suppliers in particular. The G-Cloud &lt;a rel="external" href="http://govstore.service.gov.uk/cloudstore/"&gt;Cloudstore&lt;/a&gt; is the standout success in this regard with spend of over £190 million to date – 56% of which has gone to &lt;abbr title="small and medium enterprises"&gt;SMEs&lt;/abbr&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The IT sector is one of the real success stories for government in its aim of helping more small businesses win public sector contracts. Jadu, a Leicester based &lt;abbr title="small and medium enterprise"&gt;SME&lt;/abbr&gt;, won a contract with the Ministry of Justice through &lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/how-to-use-cloudstore"&gt;G-Cloud&lt;/a&gt; to develop a digital service for employment tribunals. The company has estimated that this digital service will save the taxpayer £74 million and the project will be implemented a full year earlier than with the alternative supplier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="cabinet-office-sme-panel-members"&gt;Cabinet Office &lt;abbr title="small and medium enterprise"&gt;SME&lt;/abbr&gt; Panel members&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;table&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Steven Anderson&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Smith &amp;amp; Milton Design Agency&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Mark Bowers&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Redfern Travel Ltd&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Tim Campbell&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Bright Idea Trust&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Pamela Cook&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Infoshare Ltd&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Tony Cunningham&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Eliesha Training Ltd&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Geoff Davies&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;WWAM Writers Ltd&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Dan Gregory&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Social Enterprise Coalition&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;John Harvey&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;IRIS Consulting&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Jon Harvey&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Jon Harvey Associates Ltd&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Clare Hill&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Sysdoc Ltd&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Trevor Hursthouse&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Lingwood Management Services&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;David Johnston&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Applied Network Solutions Ltd&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Steve Kingan&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Nexor Ltd&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Sarla Langdon&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Markmaid Marketing&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Jonathan Lewis&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;The Live group plc&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Piers Linney&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Outsourcery&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Walter Menteth&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;AndArchitects&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Sara Murray&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Buddi&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Manuel Nogueira&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;AndArchitects&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;David Pearson&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Premier Partnership&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Bhagiyash Shah&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Prederi&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Elizabeth Vega&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Informed Solutions&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Sue Waller&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Knowledge Powered Solutions&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;John Young&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Edenvale Young Associates&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:www.gov.uk,2005:AnnouncementPresenter/251986</id>
    <published>2014-07-28T13:42:20+01:00</published>
    <updated>2014-07-28T13:42:20+01:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/immigration-minister-announces-new-improvements-to-the-visa-system-in-china"/>
    <title>News story: Immigration Minister announces new improvements to the visa system in China.</title>
    <category label="News story" term="News story"/>
    <summary>James Brokenshire is currently in Beijing to promote the UK’s visa service to key tourism and business partners.</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class="govspeak"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="mobile-biometrics-to-be-available-in-all-12-visa-application-centres"&gt;Mobile biometrics to be available in all 12 visa application centres&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The popular mobile biometric service, which allows customers to give their fingerprints and details to visa staff in offices, will be available at all 12 of the regions served by our visa application centres. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The service has already been successful in Shanghai and Beijing with customers complimenting the service for being convenient and easy to use. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="hour-visa-service-to-be-available-for-most-visit-and-work-visas"&gt;24 hour visa service to be available for most visit and work visas&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Minister also announced that the 24 hour Super Priority Visa would be available to customers in Beijing, Shanghai and Guangzhou. The 24 hour service, only available for UK visas, will be open to customers applying for the majority of visit visa and work visa categories.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Immigration and Security Minister James Brokenshire said:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;China is the UK’s largest visa market and the number of business travellers and tourists we welcome continues to grow - demand for visitor visas increased by 40% in the last year alone.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;We already offer an excellent visa service in China and through the 24 hour visa service and the expansion of mobile biometrics, business visitors will be able to apply for their visas more quickly and easily.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p class="last-child"&gt;We want to make sure that we offer our Chinese customers a world class service and we will continue to make improvements so that our visa system is as efficient as possible, while at the same time protecting British borders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other recent improvements we have made to the visa service include: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Upgrading our 12 visa application centres and offering out of working hours appointments;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Extending our three to five day priority service (used by  over 7,000 people In June 2014 alone);&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Introducing the passport pass-back service, allowing customers to apply for the UK and Schengen visa at the same time;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The launch of a new online application form, with fewer questions,  translated guidance and giving the option of pre-populating a Schengen form at the same time;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Offering Premium service lounges in Beijing, Shanghai and Guangzhou visa application centres, reducing waiting times for applicants and offering personalised assistance at every stage;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Developing a dedicated team based in the British Embassy in Beijing which supports business, tourism and education sectors with their visa needs;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Reducing documentary requirements for the Chinese government-endorsed Approved Destination Scheme (ADS) for Chinese tour groups and repeat travellers.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:www.gov.uk,2005:AnnouncementPresenter/220343</id>
    <published>2014-02-24T12:58:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2014-07-28T13:24:04+01:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/vehicle-tax-changes"/>
    <title>News story: Vehicle tax changes</title>
    <category label="News story" term="News story"/>
    <summary>Updates and advice on abolition of the vehicle tax disc. </summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Updated:&lt;/em&gt; Sentence added - Customers with a Northern Ireland address will still need to display their MoT disc.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="govspeak"&gt;&lt;p&gt;From 1 October 2014, the paper tax disc will no longer need to be displayed on a vehicle windscreen. Customers with a Northern Ireland address will still need to display their MoT disc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class="call-to-action"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can apply &lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/tax-disc"&gt;online&lt;/a&gt; to tax or SORN your vehicle using your 16 digit reference number from your vehicle tax renewal reminder (V11) or 11 digit reference number from your log book (V5C)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id="what-this-means-to-you"&gt;What this means to you&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To drive or keep a vehicle on the road you will still need to get vehicle tax and &lt;abbr title="Driver and Vehicle Licensing Agency"&gt;DVLA&lt;/abbr&gt; will still send you a renewal reminder when your vehicle tax is due to expire. This applies to all types of vehicles including those that are exempt from payment of vehicle tax. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="buying-a-vehicle"&gt;Buying a vehicle&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From 1 October, when you buy a vehicle, the vehicle tax will no longer be transferred with the vehicle. You will need to get new vehicle tax before you can use the vehicle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can tax the vehicle using the New Keeper Supplement (V5C/2) part of the vehicle registration certificate (V5C) online or by phone - 24 hours a day, 7 days a week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alternatively,  you may wish to visit a Post Office® branch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="selling-a-vehicle"&gt;Selling a vehicle&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you sell a vehicle after 1 October and you have notified &lt;abbr title="Driver and Vehicle Licensing Agency"&gt;DVLA&lt;/abbr&gt;, you will automatically get a refund for any full calendar months left on the vehicle tax. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="vehicle-tax-refunds"&gt;Vehicle tax refunds&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You will no longer need to make a separate application for a refund of vehicle tax. &lt;abbr title="Driver and Vehicle Licensing Agency"&gt;DVLA&lt;/abbr&gt; will automatically issue a refund when a notification is received from the person named on &lt;abbr title="Driver and Vehicle Licensing Agency"&gt;DVLA&lt;/abbr&gt; vehicle register that the:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;vehicle has been sold or transferred &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;vehicle has been scrapped at an Automated Treatment Facility&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;vehicle has been exported &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;vehicle has been removed from the road and the person on the vehicle register has made a Statutory Off Road Notification (SORN)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;person on the vehicle register has changed the tax class on the vehicle to an exempt duty tax class&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2 id="paying-vehicle-tax-by-direct-debit"&gt;Paying vehicle tax by Direct Debit&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From 1 October 2014 (5 October if setting up at a Post Office®), Direct Debit will be offered as an additional way to pay for vehicle tax. This will be available for customers who need to tax their vehicle from 1 November 2014:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;annually&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;6 monthly&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;monthly (12 months tax paid for on a monthly basis) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Provided an MOT remains valid, the payments will continue automatically until you tell &lt;abbr title="Driver and Vehicle Licensing Agency"&gt;DVLA&lt;/abbr&gt; to stop taking them or you cancel the Direct Debit with your bank. Valid insurance should also be in place for vehicles registered in Northern Ireland.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Direct Debit will be cancelled and payments automatically stopped when you tell &lt;abbr title="Driver and Vehicle Licensing Agency"&gt;DVLA&lt;/abbr&gt; that you no longer have the vehicle, or the vehicle has been taken off the road and a Statutory Off Road Notification (SORN) has been made.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="when-the-direct-debit-scheme-cant-be-used"&gt;When the Direct Debit scheme can’t be used&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Paying by Direct Debit will not be available to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;first registration vehicles&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;fleet schemes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
&lt;abbr title="Heavy Goods Vehicles"&gt;HGVs&lt;/abbr&gt; (paying the Road User Levy)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3 id="checking-the-tax-status-of-a-vehicle"&gt;Checking the tax status of a vehicle&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can check the tax status of any vehicle &lt;a href="http://www.gov.uk/check-vehicle-tax"&gt;online&lt;/a&gt;. This can also be used for rental vehicles.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:www.gov.uk,2005:AnnouncementPresenter/251522</id>
    <published>2014-07-28T13:11:46+01:00</published>
    <updated>2014-07-28T13:11:46+01:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/june-2014-market-trend-data"/>
    <title>Press release: June 2014 Market Trend Data</title>
    <category label="Press release" term="Press release"/>
    <summary>Land Registry's Market Trend Data for England and Wales.</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class="govspeak"&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Average house price in England and Wales now £172,011 compared with the peak of £181,466 in November 2007&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Annual growth of 6.4 per cent in June&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The June data shows no change in monthly price &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;898 repossessions in England &amp;amp; Wales during April 2014&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Over 78,530 residential properties in England and Wales lodged for registration in June ranging from £11,500 to £20,150,000&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;The June data from Land Registry’s House Price Index shows an annual price increase of 6.4 per cent which takes the average property value in England and Wales to £172,011. There is no monthly change from May to June. Repossession volumes decreased by 30 per cent in April 2014 to 898 compared with 1,285 in April 2013. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The region in England and Wales which experienced the greatest increase in its average property value over the last 12 months is London with a movement of 16.4 per cent. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;West Midlands experienced the greatest monthly rise with a movement of 1.9 per cent.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;North East saw the lowest annual price growth with a movement of 0.8 per cent.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Yorkshire &amp;amp; The Humber saw the most significant monthly price fall of 1.3 per cent.  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The most up-to-date figures available show that during April 2014 the number of completed house sales in England &amp;amp; Wales increased by 31 per cent to 66,659 compared with 51,022 in April 2013.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The number of properties sold in England and Wales for over £1 million in April 2014 increased by 39 per cent to 1,028 from 740 in April 2013.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The region with the greatest fall in repossession sales in April 2014 was the West Midlands.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel="external" href="http://www.landregistry.gov.uk/public/house-prices-and-sales"&gt;Access the full dataset&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Region&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Monthly change since May 2014&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Annual change since June 2013&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Average price June 2014&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;West Midlands&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;1.9%&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;4.7%&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;£135,228&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;South East&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;0.6%&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;7.8%&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;£228,109&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;London&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;0.1%&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;16.4%&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;£437,608&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;England and  Wales&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;0.0%&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;6.4%&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;£172,011&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Wales&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;-0.3%&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;2.7%&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;£117,440&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;North West&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;-0.4%&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;2.2%&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;£109,905&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;East&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;-0.4%&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;7.9%&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;£187,820&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;South West&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;-0.9%&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;5.4%&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;£180,880&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;East Midlands&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;-1.0%&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;6.4%&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;£129,030&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;North East&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;-1.0%&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;0.8%&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;£98,555&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Yorkshire and  The Humber&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;-1.3%&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;3.4%&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;£118,699&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;&lt;h2 id="average-price-by-property-type-2014-to-2013"&gt;Average price by property type 2014 to 2013&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Average price by property type (England and Wales)&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;June 2014&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;June 2013&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Difference (%)&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Detached&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;£270,496&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;£256,225&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;5.6%&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Semi-detached&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;£162,545&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;£153,092&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;6.2%&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Terraced&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;£129,486&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;£121,822&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;6.3%&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Flat/maisonette&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;£164,967&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;£153,289&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;7.6%&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;All&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;£172,011&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;£161,716&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6.4%&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;&lt;h2 id="sales-volumes-2013-to-2012"&gt;Sales volumes 2013 to 2012&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Month&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Sales 2013 England and Wales&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Sales 2012 England and Wales&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Difference&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;January&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;43,389&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;43,785&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;-1%&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;February&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;45,252&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;44,874&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;1%&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;March&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;54,724&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;61,379&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;-11%&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;April&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;51,022&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;43,281&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;18%&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;May&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;66,312&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;52,560&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;26%&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;June&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;66,089&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;59,901&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;10%&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;July&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;73,694&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;59,181&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;25%&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;August&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;79,482&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;65,055&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;22%&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;September&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;69,884&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;52,896&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;32%&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;October&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;77,120&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;59,251&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;30%&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;November&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;83,304&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;63,997&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;30%&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;December&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;79,820&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;56,728&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;41%&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Total&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;790,092&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;662,888&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;19%&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;&lt;h2 id="sales-volumes-2014-to-2013"&gt;Sales volumes 2014 to 2013&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Month&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Sales 2014 England and Wales&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Sales 2013 England and Wales&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Difference&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;January&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;65,480&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;43,389&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;51%&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;February&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;64,739&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;45,252&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;43%&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;March&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;65,837&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;54,724&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;20%&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;April&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;66,659&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;51,022&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;31%&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;&lt;h2 id="repossessions-by-region-2014-to-2013"&gt;Repossessions by region 2014 to 2013&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Repossessions by region&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;April 2014&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;April 2013&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Difference&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;East&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;76&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;103&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;-26%&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;East Midlands&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;74&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;123&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;-40%&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;London&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;72&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;106&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;-32%&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;North East&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;23&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;39&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;-41%&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;North West&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;238&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;277&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;-14%&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;South East&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;85&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;142&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;-40%&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;South West&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;65&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;89&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;-27%&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Wales&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;74&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;86&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;-14%&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;West Midlands&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;86&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;151&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;-43%&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Yorkshire and  The Humber&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;105&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;169&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;-38%&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;All&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;898&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1,285&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;-30%&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Price Paid Data includes details of over 78,530 residential property sales in England and Wales lodged for registration in June 2014. The most expensive sale in June 2014 was located in Knightsbridge, London SW1 and sold for £11.75m. The cheapest sale in June 2014 was located near Choppington in Northumberland and sold for £11,500.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel="external" href="http://www.landregistry.gov.uk/market-trend-data/public-data/price-paid-data/download"&gt;Access the full dataset&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id="notes-to-editors"&gt;Notes to editors&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Market Trend Data is published on the twentieth working day of each month. The July House Price Index (HPI) and Price Paid data set will be published at 9.30am on Friday 29 August 2014. The release calendar up to May 2015 is published at &lt;a rel="external" href="http://www.landregistry.gov.uk/public/house-prices-and-sales/land-registry-house-price-index-release-calendar"&gt;http://www.landregistry.gov.uk/public/house-prices-and-sales/land-registry-house-price-index-release-calendar&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Publication of the Transaction Data has moved so that it is now available on the fifteenth working day of the month. This means that the June transaction dataset will be published on 21 August 2014 at 11am. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;HPI&lt;/strong&gt; uses a sample size that is larger than all other statistical measures available. It is calculated using Land Registry’s dataset of all residential property sales completed in England and Wales since January 1995.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Land Registry’s dataset contains details on over 19 million residential transactions. Of these, over 7 million are identifiable matched pairs, providing the basis for the repeat sales regression analysis used to complete the index. This technique of quality adjustment ensures an “apples to apples” comparison between properties.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The adjusted headline statistics for England and Wales on p14 of the monthly HPI report include additional repossession data. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The repossession data is based on the number of transactions lodged with Land Registry by lenders exercising their power of sale. Once we have identified these transactions, we extract the price paid information from the related register entry. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Although the HPI goes back to January 1995, we have only been recording repossessions comprehensively since 2006. This means that historic repossession data is not available prior to January 2006. See &lt;a rel="external" href="http://www.landregistry.gov.uk/public/house-prices-and-sales/about-hpi"&gt;About HPI&lt;/a&gt; for more information.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
&lt;a rel="external" href="http://www.landregistry.gov.uk/public/information/public-data/hpi-background"&gt;HPI background tables&lt;/a&gt; are available as Open Data in Excel and CSV formats and in machine readable format as linked data&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Price Paid Data&lt;/strong&gt; is residential property price data for all the residential property sales in England and Wales that are lodged with us for registration in that month. The following information is available for each property:
    &lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the full address &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;the price paid &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;the date of transfer&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;the property type&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;whether it is new build or not &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;whether it is freehold or leasehold&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Price Paid Data can be &lt;a rel="external" href="http://www.landregistry.gov.uk/market-trend-data/public-data/price-paid-data/download"&gt;downloaded in csv format and in a machine readable format as linked data&lt;/a&gt;. It is available for anyone to examine or re-use free of charge under the OGL.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;As a government department established in 1862, executive agency and trading fund responsible to the Secretary of State for Business, Innovation and Skills, Land Registry keeps and maintains the Land Register for England and Wales. The Land Register has been an open document since 1990.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;With the largest transactional database of its kind detailing around 24 million titles, Land Registry underpins the economy by safeguarding ownership of many billions of pounds worth of property.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;For further information about Land Registry visit &lt;a rel="external" href="http://www.landregistry.gov.uk"&gt;www.landregistry.gov.uk&lt;/a&gt;. Follow us on &lt;a rel="external" href="http://twitter.com/landreggov"&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;, our &lt;a rel="external" href="http://blog.landregistry.gov.uk/"&gt;blog&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a rel="external" href="http://www.linkedin.com/company/land-registry"&gt;LinkedIn&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a rel="external" href="http://www.facebook.com/pages/Land-Registry/343223435769541"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;h4 id="contact"&gt;Contact&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;div class="contact postal-address" id="contact_2010"&gt;
  &lt;div class="content"&gt;
    &lt;h3&gt;Press office&lt;/h3&gt;

    &lt;div class="vcard contact-inner"&gt;
        &lt;p class="adr"&gt;
&lt;span class="fn"&gt;Marion Shelley&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;span class="street-address"&gt;Trafalgar House
&lt;br&gt;
1 Bedford Park
&lt;br&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;span class="locality"&gt;Croydon&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;span class="postal-code"&gt;CR0 2AQ&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;


        &lt;div class="email-url-number"&gt;
            &lt;p class="email"&gt;
              &lt;span class="type"&gt;Email&lt;/span&gt;
              &lt;a class="email" href="mailto:marion.shelley@landregistry.gsi.gov.uk"&gt;marion.shelley@landregistry.gsi.gov.uk&lt;/a&gt;
            &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p class="tel"&gt;
              &lt;span class="type"&gt;Telephone&lt;/span&gt;
              0300 0067543
            &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p class="tel"&gt;
              &lt;span class="type"&gt;Mobile&lt;/span&gt;
              07790 690297
            &lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;


    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:www.gov.uk,2005:AnnouncementPresenter/251554</id>
    <published>2014-07-28T12:30:09+01:00</published>
    <updated>2014-07-28T12:30:09+01:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/eid-al-fitr-2014-prime-ministers-message"/>
    <title>News story: Eid al-Fitr 2014: Prime Minister's message</title>
    <category label="News story" term="News story"/>
    <summary>David Cameron has recorded a video message for Eid al-Fitr to wish Muslims in the UK and around the world "Eid Mubarak".</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class="govspeak"&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel="external" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ZcsCIuHAyOA"&gt;Eid al-Fitr 2014: David Cameron’s message&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="video-transcript"&gt;Video transcript&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I want to send my best wishes to Muslims across the country and around the world celebrating Eid. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This Ramadan, British Muslims have shown what Islam is all about. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve seen an inspiring amount of charity - with Muslims across the country giving what they can and giving up their own time for those less fortunate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve seen a commitment to contemplation - and Muslims have been putting themselves second as they pray, abstain and fast during the holy month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Third, we’ve seen a dedication to community - and once again this year British Muslims have opened their doors to those of all backgrounds as part of the Big Iftar, breaking bread and breaking down barriers in mosques, in community centres, in parks – even at a synagogue in north London. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s been a challenging month – especially during those long summer days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So it is fantastic to see so many British Muslims –and those of other faiths and none – come together to celebrate at this special time. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once again, to everyone who is celebrating, Eid Mubarak. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:www.gov.uk,2005:AnnouncementPresenter/251930</id>
    <published>2014-07-28T12:21:51+01:00</published>
    <updated>2014-07-28T12:21:51+01:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/government-chemist-conference-2014"/>
    <title>News story: Government Chemist Conference 2014</title>
    <category label="News story" term="News story"/>
    <summary>A 2-day conference 'Beating the cheats: Quality, safety and authenticity in the food chain' will take place on 24 and 25 November 2014.</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class="govspeak"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Scientists, regulators, enforcement agencies, industry and policy makers are invited to join the Government Chemist for the 2014 conference at The Royal Society, London to discuss topics relating to food fraud, food authenticity and food safety.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="how-much-it-costs"&gt;How much it costs&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2 days: £160 + VAT
1 day: £100 + VAT&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Conference dinner on 24 November: £55 + VAT&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="conference-venue"&gt;Conference venue&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Royal Society,
Carlton House Terrace,
London,
SW1Y 5AG&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="book-your-place"&gt;Book your place&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To reserve a place at the conference download the flyer and booking form and send it via email or post to the Government Chemist Personal Assistant. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;section class="attachment embedded" id="attachment_650441"&gt;&lt;div class="attachment-thumb"&gt;
      &lt;a href="/government/uploads/system/uploads/attachment_data/file/337180/GC_Conference_1st_Circular_LR_form.pdf" aria-describedby="attachment-650441-accessibility-help" class="thumbnail"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://assets.digital.cabinet-office.gov.uk/government/uploads/system/uploads/attachment_data/file/337180/thumbnail_GC_Conference_1st_Circular_LR_form.pdf.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div class="attachment-details"&gt;
    &lt;h2 class="title"&gt;&lt;a href="/government/uploads/system/uploads/attachment_data/file/337180/GC_Conference_1st_Circular_LR_form.pdf" aria-describedby="attachment-650441-accessibility-help"&gt;Government Chemist Conference 2014&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
    &lt;p class="metadata"&gt;
        &lt;span class="type"&gt;&lt;abbr title="Portable Document Format"&gt;PDF&lt;/abbr&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class="file-size"&gt;394KB&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class="page-length"&gt;2 pages&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;/p&gt;


      &lt;div class="accessibility-warning js-toggle-accessibility-warning" id="attachment-650441-accessibility-help"&gt;
        &lt;h2&gt;This file may not be suitable for users of assistive technology.
          &lt;span class="toggler"&gt;Request a different format.&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;/h2&gt;
        &lt;p class="help-block"&gt;
          If you use assistive technology and need a version of this document
in a more accessible format, please email
&lt;a href="mailto:government.chemist@lgcgroup.com?body=Details%20of%20document%20required%3A%0A%0A%20%20Title%3A%20Government%20Chemist%20Conference%202014%0A%20%20Original%20format%3A%20pdf%0A%0APlease%20tell%20us%3A%0A%0A%20%201.%20What%20makes%20this%20format%20unsuitable%20for%20you%3F%0A%20%202.%20What%20format%20you%20would%20prefer%3F%0A%20%20%20%20%20%20&amp;amp;subject=Request%20for%20%27Government%20Chemist%20Conference%202014%27%20in%20an%20alternative%20format"&gt;government.chemist@lgcgroup.com&lt;/a&gt;.
Please tell us what format you need. It will help us if you say what assistive technology you use.

        &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;div class="contact postal-address" id="contact_2064"&gt;
  &lt;div class="content"&gt;
    &lt;h3&gt;Government Chemist Personal Assistant&lt;/h3&gt;

    &lt;div class="vcard contact-inner"&gt;
        &lt;p class="adr"&gt;
&lt;span class="fn"&gt;Sian Smith&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;span class="street-address"&gt;LGC
&lt;br&gt;
Queens Road&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;span class="locality"&gt;Teddington&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;span class="region"&gt;Middlesex&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;span class="postal-code"&gt;TW11 0LY&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;


        &lt;div class="email-url-number"&gt;
            &lt;p class="email"&gt;
              &lt;span class="type"&gt;Email&lt;/span&gt;
              &lt;a class="email" href="mailto:sian.smith@lgcgroup.com"&gt;sian.smith@lgcgroup.com&lt;/a&gt;
            &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p class="tel"&gt;
              &lt;span class="type"&gt;Telephone&lt;/span&gt;
              020 8943 7681
            &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p class="tel"&gt;
              &lt;span class="type"&gt;Fax&lt;/span&gt;
              020 8943 2767
            &lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;


    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Government Chemist will open the conference before a keynote presentation by Professor Chris Elliott who undertook the Elliott Review into the integrity and assurance of food supply networks. The conference programme will link the themes of quality, safety and authenticity in the food supply network and will include presentations on:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;government food integrity and authenticity programmes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;food information regulations&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;referee case outcomes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;quantification of meat species DNA&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;allergen detection&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3 id="who-should-attend"&gt;Who should attend?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The conference will be of interest to anyone involved in ensuring the safety, quality and authenticity of food and animal feeds including:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;food and feed industry	&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;government&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;food retailers	&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;consumer groups&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;public analysts	&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;food scientists&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;trading standards officers	&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;academics and the research community&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;environmental health officers	&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:www.gov.uk,2005:AnnouncementPresenter/251973</id>
    <published>2014-07-28T12:17:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2014-07-28T12:17:00+01:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/eid-messages-2014"/>
    <title>News story: Eid messages 2014</title>
    <category label="News story" term="News story"/>
    <summary>Ministers give their best wishes to Muslims in the UK and across the world for Eid.</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class="govspeak"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Minister for Communities Stephen Williams said:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;As millions of Muslims in the UK and around the world mark Eid, the end of Ramadan, today I would like to wish you all a happy and joyous day. Whilst many people will have marked Ramadan by a period of peaceful prayer, thought and abstention I would also like to pause for thought for people in the middle east – many Muslim, but also many of other religions or none – who have not had the fortune of a peaceful month, and we all hope that peace and stability will soon return there.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;At home we have been fortunate and privileged to enjoy a peaceful Ramadan, and many mosques embraced the opportunity to open their doors to their community and hold a ‘big iftar’ welcoming in people from the area for the daily fast breaking meal.  Many mosques and their worshippers will also have used Ramadan as a period where thinking of others come before oneself, including through increased charitable donations to both Muslim and non-religious charities. All of this furthers my already strong belief that Muslim values and British values can go hand in hand.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p class="last-child"&gt;Eid Mubarak.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Video message by Secretary of State, Eric Pickles:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel="external" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=DsrWrYG5yW8&amp;amp;list=UUT-cppgX-lbLOcIWRHmxirQ"&gt;Secretary of State Eric Pickles&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Video message by Minister of State for Faith and Communities, Baroness Warsi:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel="external" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=2M1wSOuCVzw&amp;amp;list=UUT-cppgX-lbLOcIWRHmxirQ"&gt;Minister of State for Faith and Communities Baronees Warsi&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Video message by Lord Ahmad of Wimbledon:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel="external" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=7fN-J9NQCM4&amp;amp;list=UUT-cppgX-lbLOcIWRHmxirQ"&gt;Lord Ahmad of Wimbledon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:www.gov.uk,2005:AnnouncementPresenter/251963</id>
    <published>2014-07-28T11:51:05+01:00</published>
    <updated>2014-07-28T11:51:05+01:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/car-clubs-cash-boost"/>
    <title>Press release: Car clubs cash boost</title>
    <category label="Press release" term="Press release"/>
    <summary>£500,000 to support car clubs Baroness Kramer announces.</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class="govspeak"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Car clubs are set to receive a £500,000 boost to drive forward their work, Transport Minister Baroness Kramer has announced.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As part of a wider visit to Norfolk today (28 July 2014), the minister announced that the Department for Transport will provide the funding to support 2 pilot programmes which will promote much wider access to car clubs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Baroness Kramer said: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Car clubs cut congestion, reduce carbon and save people money while still giving people the freedom and flexibility to use a car when they want to. Interest in car clubs is already gathering pace and we want to give that interest added momentum.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p class="last-child"&gt;This funding will highlight their many advantages to even more people and help take car clubs up a gear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The proportion of carless households has been growing across the country since 2005. At the same time, because people value the convenience that access to a car brings, interest in car clubs is growing. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are already over 150,000 car club members in England and government is keen to support their growth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They make much more efficient use of the limited space available on the road, with estimates suggesting that one rental car can take the place of 17 individually owned vehicles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Car clubs can also help save drivers money – potentially thousands of pounds per year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The evidence suggests that pay-as-you-go car use encourages people to walk and cycle more often and make more frequent use of public transport.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And car club vehicles tend to have lower emissions than the average car.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Department for Transport is already funding 48 car club and car sharing schemes through our &lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/speeches/local-sustainable-transport-fund-2015-to-2016"&gt;Local Sustainable Transport Fund&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While in Norfolk, Baroness Kramer also saw first hand the success of a government-funded trial of the holdall smartcard scheme which allows people to use many of the county’s different bus services with a single card. Norfolk was chosen to host the trial because of its mix of small, medium and large bus operators running services in both urban and rural areas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The experience gathered from the £2.5 million scheme will help inform the introduction of smart ticketing elsewhere in the country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The minister also visited Zenos Cars, a company that has received £150,000 towards the development of an ultra-light sports car. The technological advances are expected to inform the future development of electric cars and other ultra low emission vehicles, where the use of light weight materials is particularly valuable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class="contact" id="contact_1016"&gt;
  &lt;div class="content"&gt;
    &lt;h3&gt;Local transport media enquiries&lt;/h3&gt;

    &lt;div class="vcard contact-inner"&gt;

        &lt;div class="email-url-number"&gt;
            &lt;p class="tel"&gt;
              &lt;span class="type"&gt;Press enquiries&lt;/span&gt;
              020 7944 3118
            &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p class="tel"&gt;
              &lt;span class="type"&gt;Out of hours&lt;/span&gt;
              020 7944 4292
            &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p class="tel"&gt;
              &lt;span class="type"&gt;Public enquiries&lt;/span&gt;
              0300 330 3000
            &lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;


    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:www.gov.uk,2005:AnnouncementPresenter/251960</id>
    <published>2014-07-28T11:16:39+01:00</published>
    <updated>2014-07-28T11:16:39+01:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/the-planning-inspectorates-director-for-wales-to-retire"/>
    <title>Press release: The Planning Inspectorate’s Director for Wales to retire</title>
    <category label="Press release" term="Press release"/>
    <summary>Richard Poppleton, Director for The Planning Inspectorate, Wales, has elected to retire at the end of September 2014. </summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class="govspeak"&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Planning Inspectorate has announced that Richard Poppleton, Director for The Planning Inspectorate, Wales, has elected to retire at the end of September 2014. Tony Thickett has been appointed to replace him and will take up his duties this Autumn. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having joined the Planning Inspectorate in 1990 after a career in local government, Richard retires after more than 40 years in public service, the last 2½ years of which have been as Director for Wales. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tony Thickett graduated in 1983 with a degree in Urban and Regional Planning, and a BA in Town Planning in 1985. He became a chartered member of the Royal Town Planning Institute in 1986 and started his planning career in local government before joining the Planning Inspectorate in 1999. His first 10 years as an Inspector were spent working throughout England on appeal and development plan casework, before transferring to the Wales directorate in 2009. Until 2012, he was actively involved in reviewing the guidance and implementing the changes to the examination process of local development plans in Wales. He also conducted a number of examinations in North and South Wales and a wide range of appeal casework. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tony is returning to Wales after undertaking development plan examinations and other appeal casework in England. He therefore brings with him a breadth of planning experience both in England and Wales that will be of great assistance in responding to the emerging reforms to the planning system now being considered by the Welsh Government.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On announcing Richard’s retirement and Tony’s appointment, Simon Ridley, The Planning Inspectorate’s Chief Executive said:
“During his time as Director for Wales, Richard has strengthened links with our key partners and prepared our operations for the challenges that lie ahead.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Tony’s drive and determination will build upon Richard’s work in shaping the Inspectorate in Wales, Tony will continue to bring forward organisational and operational changes that the proposed planning reforms in Wales are likely to require.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ends&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Journalists wanting further information should contact the Planning Inspectorate’s Press Office, on: 0303 444 5004 or 0303 444 5005 or 0303 444 5082 or email: &lt;a href="mailto:pressoffice@pins.gsi.gov.uk"&gt;pressoffice@pins.gsi.gov.uk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Notes for Editors&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pictures available upon request&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:www.gov.uk,2005:AnnouncementPresenter/251970</id>
    <published>2014-07-28T11:07:52+01:00</published>
    <updated>2014-07-28T11:07:52+01:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/drivers-reminded-of-m56-weekend-closure-at-manchester-airport-junction"/>
    <title>Press release: Drivers reminded of M56 weekend closure at Manchester Airport junction</title>
    <category label="Press release" term="Press release"/>
    <summary>Drivers across the North West are being reminded that the M56 will be closed near Manchester Airport this weekend as the Highways Agency demolishes a bridge as part of its £5.5m pinch point improvement in the area.
</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class="govspeak"&gt;&lt;p&gt;The motorway will be totally closed in both directions between junction 5 at Manchester Airport and junction 6 at Hale for up to 55 hours from 10pm on Friday night (Friday 1 August) and may be closed until 5am on Monday morning (4 August).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Drivers needing to access the airport from the M60 and Manchester will still be able to use the airport spur from the westbound M56 at junction 5.  However, people heading towards the airport along the eastbound M56 from North Wales and Liverpool will need to leave at junction 6 for Hale and follow the short diversion using Runger Lane.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People travelling to the airport are being urged to leave extra time for journeys and check traffic conditions before setting out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Drivers not needing to access the airport are strongly advised to avoid this section of the M56 over the weekend – people usually using the M56 to travel beyond Manchester Airport in either direction will be directed instead to use the M6, M62 and M60 instead via Lymm (M56), Croft (M62) and Eccles (M60) interchanges.   Local diversions will also be in place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More details of the work are available on the &lt;a rel="external" href="http://www.highways.gov.uk/roads/road-projects/m56-thorley-lane-scheme/"&gt;Highways Agency’s website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Highways Agency is replacing the bridge in a £5.5m government ‘pinch-point’ initiative aimed at stimulating the creation of 3,000 new jobs at Davenport Green and Airport City by 2030 plus 5,650 homes around Altrincham, Bowdon and Hale by 2026&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Installation of the new bridge has been pencilled in for November with further weekend closures of the motorway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The project is one of 123 in the Government’s £317 million ‘pinch-point’ initiative – a two-year programme of targeted work being delivered alongside larger schemes and routine maintenance and improvements along the strategic road network.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The pinch-point programme, devised with the input of councils and local enterprise partnerships, is designed to help stimulate new development and local economic growth by improving road safety and tackling congestion bottle-necks.  In all, 28 projects, worth £66 million, are being delivered across the North West.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id="general-enquiries"&gt;General enquiries&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Members of the public should contact the Highways Agency Information Line on 0300 123 5000.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id="media-enquiries"&gt;Media enquiries&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Journalists should contact the Highways Agency press office on 0844 693 1448 and use the menu to speak to the most appropriate press officer.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:www.gov.uk,2005:AnnouncementPresenter/251948</id>
    <published>2014-07-28T11:07:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2014-07-28T11:07:00+01:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/businesses-get-greater-say-on-how-regulaton-is-enforced"/>
    <title>Press release: Businesses get greater say on how regulation is enforced</title>
    <category label="Press release" term="Press release"/>
    <summary>The Fresh Produce Consortium and the National Farmers’ Union have been selected to run reviews under Business Focus on Enforcement.</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class="govspeak"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Business Minister Matthew Hancock today (28 July 2014) hailed a change that puts business in charge of driving reform as he approved bids by business bodies to review enforcement of regulation in their sectors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a significant shift, business groups will collect and present evidence directly to ministers and to regulators. In response to each review’s findings, in the first instance the fresh produce and livestock farming sectors, departments and regulators will propose how they will address the issues identified during the reviews, lightening needless burdens without weakening essential controls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two trade bodies have been selected to run reviews under Business Focus on Enforcement: The Fresh Produce Consortium and the National Farmers’ Union (&lt;abbr title="National Farmers’ Union"&gt;NFU&lt;/abbr&gt;). &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two reviews launch today: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The Fresh Produce Consortium will investigate reports of high or inconsistent charges at ports on imports of perishable produce; inconsistency in service levels and delays; and emerging evidence that UK businesses are choosing to present shipments for import clearance at other points of entry in the EU because they can obtain a cheaper, more efficient service overseas.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The &lt;abbr title="National Farmers’ Union"&gt;NFU&lt;/abbr&gt; will gather evidence from stakeholders including farmers to investigate claims of reported duplications, overlaps and inconsistencies in visits to livestock farms by national and local regulators. Starting with farmers’ own experiences, it will seek evidence of, for example, processes and equipment checked, and data requested during local authority visits.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;After a period of evidence gathering which will run until autumn 2014, the Fresh Produce Consortium and &lt;abbr title="National Farmers’ Union"&gt;NFU&lt;/abbr&gt; will report their findings direct to ministers and regulators.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Business Minister Matthew Hancock said:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;We are changing the way Whitehall works, listening directly to business to help them grow, create prosperity and jobs. Businesses will now have the power to lead the reform of counterproductive, time consuming or bureaucratic enforcement of regulation that can get in the way of growth.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p class="last-child"&gt;Putting reputable private sector experts in the driving seat will help us improve the way regulation is enforced without compromising standards. It is all part of our unambiguously pro-business agenda to increase the financial security of the British people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Secretary of State for Environment, Food and Rural Affairs, Liz Truss said:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p class="last-child"&gt;Food and farming is our largest manufacturing industry and it is vital that our high quality products continue to be competitive. We’ve already helped farmers by cutting the number of dairy inspections by 8,000. However, I am determined to cut red tape even more so our farmers can grow their businesses and the rural economy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;abbr title="National Farmers’ Union"&gt;NFU&lt;/abbr&gt; Deputy President Minette Batters said: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p class="last-child"&gt;This is an important new initiative which gives businesses a greater role in reviewing the impact of the way regulation is enforced. We look forward to working with the Better Regulation Executive over the coming months, in gathering evidence and presenting our findings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nigel Jenney, Chief Executive of the Fresh Produce Consortium (&lt;abbr title="Fresh Produce Consortium"&gt;FPC&lt;/abbr&gt;) said:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;We welcome this innovative approach by UK government which allows industry to highlight key areas of concern and to present vital evidence on issues. We are delighted that &lt;abbr title="Fresh Produce Consortium"&gt;FPC&lt;/abbr&gt; has been successful in being selected to undertake this review.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p class="last-child"&gt;We are keen to carry out our review of the impact of charges for official controls on fresh produce imports. &lt;abbr title="Fresh Produce Consortium"&gt;FPC&lt;/abbr&gt; members have raised with us problems they experience and we want to take this opportunity to investigate further and present the findings to the minister.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Terry Scuoler, Chief Executive of EEF, the manufacturers’ organisation, acts as a champion and advocate for Business Focus on Enforcement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Terry Scuoler said:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p class="last-child"&gt;The way that regulation is enforced and applied can be more time consuming for business than the regulation itself. Putting businesses at the forefront of reform means that change will be informed by invaluable first-hand experience of the hurdles and burdens that poor enforcement can cause.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Business Focus on Enforcement builds on the successful Focus on Enforcement programme by giving trade associations and representative business groups the dominant role in identifying enforcement issues and driving reform to benefit their industries. Previous Focus on Enforcement reviews have led to more business-friendly enforcement in sectors including childcare, chemical manufacturing and for coastal investment projects and developments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="notes-to-editors"&gt;Notes to editors&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Business Focus on Enforcement reviews are funded through the &lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/contestable-policy-fund"&gt;Ministerial Contestable Policy Fund&lt;/a&gt;, set up to inject greater ambition, expertise, or a more creative range of options into the policy development process than would otherwise be available to ministers. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In March 2014, industry groups such as trade associations were invited to bid to lead 1 of 3 ‘pathfinder’ reviews, allowing them to collect evidence of the impact on industry of current enforcement practices and challenge problems like duplicated paperwork, inconsistent advice or unhelpful guidance. The successful organisations will each receive a grant of up to £4,000 to contribute towards the costs of their projects. As a minimum, the review teams will match the funding from their own resources.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Fresh Produce Consortium is the UK trade association for the fresh produce and cut flower industry. Extensive membership covers the whole spectrum of the industry, including growers, importers, wholesalers, retailers, distributors, processors, packers, food service companies and other allied organisations.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The &lt;abbr title="National Farmers’ Union"&gt;NFU&lt;/abbr&gt; champions British farming and provides professional representation and services to its farmer and grower members and has a membership of 55,000 members across England and Wales.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Focus on Enforcement reviews examine how regulation is delivered – whether through inspections, advice, or enforcement – rather than focusing on the design of the regulations themselves. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A third review will be announced later in the year (2014).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;For more information about the new project, visit &lt;a rel="external" href="http://discuss.bis.gov.uk/focusonenforcement/business-focus-on-enforcement/"&gt;Focus on Enforcement&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
