<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xml:lang="en-GB" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>tag:www.gov.uk,2005:/government/organisations/prime-ministers-office-10-downing-street</id>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.gov.uk/"/>
  <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://www.gov.uk/government/organisations/prime-ministers-office-10-downing-street.atom"/>
  <title>Prime Minister's Office, 10 Downing Street - Activity on GOV.UK</title>
  <author>
    <name>HM Government</name>
  </author>
  <updated>2014-07-29T12:47:18+01:00</updated>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:www.gov.uk,2005:NewsArticlePresenter/249131</id>
    <published>2014-07-18T12:45:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2014-07-29T12:47:18+01:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/malaysia-airlines-flight-mh17-uk-government-response"/>
    <title>News story: Malaysia Airlines flight MH17: UK government response</title>
    <category label="News story" term="News story"/>
    <summary>Latest news and travel advice relating to flight MH17, which crashed in Ukraine on 17 July 2014. This page will be updated regularly.</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Updated:&lt;/em&gt; Added joint call from 28 July.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="govspeak"&gt;&lt;h2 id="latest-news-and-statements"&gt;Latest news and statements&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id="july"&gt;28 July&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/joint-call-with-obama-merkel-hollande-and-renzi"&gt;PM joint call with President Obama, Angela Merkel, President Hollande and Prime Minister Renzi&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3 id="july-1"&gt;21 July&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/statement-on-mh17-disaster-and-israel-and-gaza-national-security-council-meeting-21-july"&gt;Statement on MH17 disaster: National Security Council Meeting&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/speeches/prime-ministers-statement-on-ukraine-and-gaza"&gt;The Prime Minister’s statement on Ukraine to the House of Commons&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3 id="july-2"&gt;20 July&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/pm-call-with-president-putin-on-the-flight-mh17-disaster"&gt;PM call with President Putin on the flight MH17 disaster&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/statement-on-the-flight-mh17-disaster-foreign-secretarys-meeting-20-july"&gt;Statement on the flight MH17 disaster: Foreign Secretary’s meeting&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/pm-calls-with-chancellor-merkel-and-president-hollande-on-flight-mh17-disaster"&gt;PM calls with Chancellor Merkel and President Hollande on flight MH17 disaster&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/mh17-air-disaster-article-by-david-cameron"&gt;MH17 air disaster: an article from David Cameron&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3 id="july-3"&gt;19 July&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/russian-ambassador-summoned-to-fco-over-flight-mh17"&gt;Russian Ambassador summoned to FCO over flight MH17&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/statement-on-the-mh17-disaster-investigation-and-pm-calls-to-other-leaders"&gt;Statement on the MH17 disaster investigation and PM calls to other leaders&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3 id="july-4"&gt;18 July&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/pm-call-with-president-obama-on-flight-mh17-disaster"&gt;PM call with President Obama on flight MH17 disaster&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/government-statement-on-the-malaysia-airlines-flight-mh17"&gt;Government statement on the Malaysia Airlines flight MH17&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/pm-calls-other-leaders-to-discuss-flight-mh17-disaster"&gt;PM calls other leaders to discuss flight MH17 disaster&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel="external" href="http://www.un.org/News/Press/docs/2014/sc11480.doc.htm"&gt;United Nations Security Council press statement on Malaysian plane crash&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/speeches/this-is-a-dark-moment-for-the-international-community"&gt;Statement by UK Ambassador Lyall Grant to the UN Security Council meeting on the situation in Ukraine&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/speeches/pm-statement-on-malaysia-airlines-flight-mh17"&gt;PM statement on Malaysia Airlines flight MH17&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3 id="july-5"&gt;17 July&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/foreign-secretary-we-believe-british-nationals-were-on-board-mh17"&gt;Foreign Secretary: We believe British nationals were on board MH17&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2 id="ukraine-travel-advice"&gt;Ukraine travel advice&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read &lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/foreign-travel-advice/ukraine"&gt;updated travel advice relating to Ukraine&lt;/a&gt; from the Foreign &amp;amp; Commonwealth Office.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class="call-to-action"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;British nationals who are concerned a friend or relative may be involved in the flight MH17 disaster should contact the Foreign Office on 020 7008 1500.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id="social-media-to-follow"&gt;Social media to follow&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To keep up to date with the latest statements and advice on Twitter, follow:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a rel="external" href="http://twitter.com/number10gov"&gt;@Number10gov&lt;/a&gt; – UK Prime Minister&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
&lt;a rel="external" href="http://twitter.com/foreignoffice"&gt;@ForeignOffice&lt;/a&gt; – Foreign &amp;amp; Commonwealth Office&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
&lt;a rel="external" href="http://twitter.com/ukinukraine"&gt;@UKinUkraine&lt;/a&gt; - British Embassy Kyiv&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:www.gov.uk,2005:NewsArticlePresenter/252081</id>
    <published>2014-07-29T09:30:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2014-07-29T09:30:00+01:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/new-measures-to-tighten-up-the-immigration-system"/>
    <title>Press release: New measures to tighten up the immigration system</title>
    <category label="Press release" term="Press release"/>
    <summary>David Cameron and Theresa May have announced changes to universities and colleges seeking sponsor status and European migrants' benefits.</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class="govspeak"&gt;&lt;p&gt;A new crackdown on immigration abuses was announced today by the Prime Minister and the Home Secretary as part of the government’s long-term economic plan to secure a better future for Britain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From November, tougher rules will be imposed on universities and colleges who sponsor international students to study in the UK.  Currently, educational institutions cannot enjoy highly trusted sponsor status if 20% or more of the individuals they have offered places to are refused visas. But that figure will be cut to 10% in November after a 3 month transitional period for colleges and universities to re-examine their admissions procedures before offering individuals places.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Prime Minister also announced plans to halve the period over which European migrants can claim benefits. From November, European jobseekers will only be able to claim Jobseekers Allowance and other key welfare benefits for a maximum period of 3 months. This follows tough changes that were announced earlier this year to introduce a minimum 3 month delay to claiming benefits and to cut off benefits after 6 months unless the individual has very clear job prospects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class="call-to-action"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The government has also launched a &lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/consultations/recruitment-sector-prohibiting-the-advertising-of-jobs-exclusively-in-other-eea-countries"&gt;consultation on banning overseas-only advertising for jobs.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Prime Minister David Cameron said:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Hardworking people expect and deserve an immigration system that puts Britain first. Over the past 4 years we have clamped down on abuses, making sure the right people are coming here for the right reasons.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p class="last-child"&gt;At the same time, as part of our long-term economic plan, we have been fixing our education, training and welfare problems with radical school reform, record numbers of apprenticeships and an employment rate that has never been higher. All of these measures will ensure British people get a fair deal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;figure class="image embedded"&gt;&lt;div class="img"&gt;&lt;img alt="Immigration officers explain their roles to David Cameron and Theresa May." src="https://assets.digital.cabinet-office.gov.uk/government/uploads/system/uploads/image_data/file/29153/Immigration_govuk2.jpg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;The new restrictions were announced as the first measures of the government’s flagship &lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/collections/immigration-bill"&gt;Immigration Act 2014&lt;/a&gt; came into force, including:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;restrictions on the abuse of Article 8 of the European Convention on Human Rights – the right to family life – by migrants to avoid deportation; in the future, judges must consider the British public interest too&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;a new system of “deport now, appeal later” which will help the authorities to remove foreign criminals; if convicted criminals want to appeal against the decision, they will have to do so from their own country &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;new powers to revoke the driving licences of illegal immigrants – a total of 3,150 have been revoked since its introduction earlier this month&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;With almost 70,000 appeals heard every year, the new Immigration Act aims to cut the current level of Article 8 legislation abuses by making sure the right to family and private life is not regarded as absolute or undisputed. Section 19 of the Act puts into statute the principle that the law should be on the side of the British public and there is an expectation that the courts should have proper regard to Parliament’s view of what the public interest requires.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other measures in the Act will further limit the benefits and services migrants can access and make it easier to remove people with no legal right to be in the UK. It will also make the UK less attractive to people who want to come here to try to exploit the system. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Home Secretary Theresa May said:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;We are building an immigration system that is fair to British citizens and legitimate migrants, but tough on those who abuse it or flout the law.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;The Immigration Act is a landmark piece of legislation that will make Britain a less attractive place for those who come here for the wrong reasons, and allow us to remove more people when they have no right to remain.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;We will always act when we see abuse of our immigration system. And that is why we are tightening the rules to cut out abuse in the student visa system.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p class="last-child"&gt;These reforms are helping to deliver what we have always promised – to build an immigration system that truly works in the national interest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The government is also today launching a &lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/consultations/recruitment-sector-prohibiting-the-advertising-of-jobs-exclusively-in-other-eea-countries"&gt;consultation on banning overseas-only advertising&lt;/a&gt; – legally requiring employment agencies to advertise in Britain, and new plans to restrict the number of Job Centre Plus jobs which are automatically advertised on an EU-wide job portal.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="notes-to-editors"&gt;Notes to editors&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Since 1 January 2014 the government has introduced a number of new measures to limit access to benefits for EU nationals and we have introduced new powers to tackle fraud and abuse. These measures are expected to save the UK taxpayer £500 million over the next 5 years:
    &lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a new minimum 3 month delay before an EU jobseeker can claim benefits and a 6 month time-limit on Jobseekers Allowance unless the EU jobseeker can show they have clear prospects of an imminent job start&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;if the EU national claims to be in work or to have recently been working we’ll apply a new Minimum Earnings Threshold of £153 per week to help decide whether the work can be treated as meaningful and effective&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;since 1 April EU jobseekers are also no longer able to claim Housing Benefit&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;on 31 Dec 2013 DCLG issued new statutory guidance to make sure local authorities set a residency requirement for qualification for social housing&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;HMRC have introduced increased compliance checks in respect of child benefit and child tax credit payments to EEA nationals &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;on 1 July HMRC also introduced a similar 3 month delay before an economically inactive EU national can claim child benefit and child tax credit&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;there is also a stronger gateway test (the Habitual Residence Test) which all migrants must satisfy in order to access benefits &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;EU nationals who are removed from the UK for not exercising Treaty rights, for example for begging or rough sleeping, will be unable to re-enter the UK for 12 months (following removal) unless they have a valid reason to be here&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;For full details of Immigration Act measures commenced today visit:
    &lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a rel="external" href="http://www.legislation.gov.uk/uksi/2014/1820/contents/made"&gt;The Immigration Act 2014 (Commencement No. 1, Transitory and Saving Provisions) Order 2014&lt;/a&gt;   &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a rel="external" href="http://www.legislation.gov.uk/uksi/2014/1943/contents/made"&gt;The Immigration Act 2014 (Commencement No. 2) Order 2014&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
&lt;a rel="external" href="http://www.legislation.gov.uk/uksi/2014/1798/contents/made"&gt;The Immigration Act 2014 (Specified Anti-fraud Organisation) Order 2014&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:www.gov.uk,2005:NewsArticlePresenter/252072</id>
    <published>2014-07-28T19:14:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2014-07-28T19:14:00+01:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/joint-call-with-obama-merkel-hollande-and-renzi"/>
    <title>Press release: Joint call with Obama, Merkel, Hollande and Renzi</title>
    <category label="Press release" term="Press release"/>
    <summary>The Prime Minister spoke to President Obama, Chancellor Merkel, President Hollande and Prime Minister Renzi in a joint call this afternoon.</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class="govspeak"&gt;&lt;p&gt;A spokesperson said:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The Prime Minister spoke to President Obama, Chancellor Merkel, President Hollande and Prime Minister Renzi in a joint call this afternoon. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The discussion focussed on the international response to the MH17 disaster and Russia’s ongoing efforts to destabilise Ukraine. They agreed that the immediate priority must be to secure unrestricted access to the MH17 crash site, both to recover any remaining victims and to allow an unimpeded investigation of the site.  They noted their support for Dutch and Australian efforts to secure such access.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“On the broader conflict in Eastern Ukraine, they agreed that Russia has failed to take the steps necessary to de-escalate the crisis, such as ceasing support for the separatists; stopping the flow of weapons across the border; and using its influence to ensure the release of hostages. Indeed the latest information from the region suggests that even since MH17 was shot down, Russia continues to transfer weapons across the border and to provide practical support to the separatists. Leaders agreed that the international community should therefore impose further costs on Russia and specifically that Ambassadors from across the EU should agree a strong package of sectoral sanctions as swiftly as possible. They agreed that the EU and United States should continue to work together to exert pressure on Russia to change course and to engage in a political resolution to the crisis before more innocent lives are lost.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class="call-to-action"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Read more about the &lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/malaysia-airlines-flight-mh17-uk-government-response"&gt;UK government response&lt;/a&gt; to the Malaysia Airlines flight MH17 disaster.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The leaders also discussed the deteriorating situation in Israel and Gaza and agreed on the urgent need for a lasting ceasefire in Gaza and Israel, backing the efforts of the Egyptian government to achieve this. They noted that the fighting will not lead to lasting peace or security for either Israelis or Palestinians.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“They also touched on Libya given the worsening security situation and agreed that the United Nations has a vital role to play to facilitate the political process that could help to restore stability in the country. Finally, they discussed the situation in Iraq and progress towards establishing an inclusive government that represents all Iraqis.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:www.gov.uk,2005:NewsArticlePresenter/244991</id>
    <published>2014-07-01T16:11:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2014-07-28T16:21:04+01:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/points-of-light-july-2014-winners"/>
    <title>News story: Points of Light: July 2014 winners</title>
    <category label="News story" term="News story"/>
    <summary>The Points of Light award recognises outstanding individuals - people who are making a change in their community and inspiring others.</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Updated:&lt;/em&gt; Added recipient number 73 - Sue Ransley.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="govspeak"&gt;&lt;p&gt;The following people were given a Points of Light award in July 2014 (the numbering continues from &lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/points-of-light-june-2014-winners"&gt;June’s winners&lt;/a&gt;):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="christine-howard-surrey"&gt;54. Christine Howard (Surrey)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Christine wins the award for helping set up both the Surrey Hills Society and the not-for-profit Surrey Hills Enterprises Community Interest Company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="jennie-williams-merseyside"&gt;55. Jennie Williams (Merseyside)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jennie wins the award for working to improve the diets of many people in her community through &lt;a rel="external" href="http://shoots-food.co.uk/"&gt;‘Shoots’.&lt;/a&gt; Jennie also helps run the local residents association and volunteers with a local youth project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="mel-woodards-somerset"&gt;56. Mel Woodards (Somerset)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mel has used her love of football to create sporting opportunities for hundreds of young people in Somerset. She decided to set up a league for younger players between 6 and 10 years old. Originally aiming to attract 100 to 200 young players to the league, Mel has now recruited her 900th player.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="maxine-green-leeds"&gt;57. Maxine Green (Leeds)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maxine wins the award for giving over 9,000 volunteering hours on a wide range of projects. In 2013 alone she raised over £700,000 for local causes. Most recently Maxine was selected as a volunteer for the 2014 &lt;a rel="external" href="http://letour.yorkshire.com/"&gt;Tour de France Grand Départ&lt;/a&gt; in Yorkshire.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="alison-grant-london"&gt;58. Alison Grant (London)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alison wins the award for helping create the largest under-16 cycling club in the country. Alison joined the &lt;a rel="external" href="http://www.slipstreamers.co.uk/hillingdonslipstreamers/"&gt;Slipstreamers Club&lt;/a&gt; 14 years ago; the Slipstreamers Go-Ride Club now has over 300 members compared to the 20 at its start in 1998.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="jake-hayman-london"&gt;59. Jake Hayman (London)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wanting to give something back to his old school, Jake organised a group of his former schoolmates to go back and provide relatable careers advice to current students. Following the event’s success Jake set up &lt;a rel="external" href="http://futurefirst.org.uk/"&gt;Future First&lt;/a&gt; to build networks of former students to do the same in other state schools.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="yvonne-jarvis-birmingham"&gt;60. Yvonne Jarvis (Birmingham)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yvonne wins the award for using her own life savings to set up the Brooke House Project in Erdington, Birmingham. Run entirely by volunteers, the Christian charity reaches out to marginalised people in the community who have dependency and behavioural issues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="tom-moore-norfolk"&gt;61. Tom Moore (Norfolk)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tom wins the award for volunteering with his local Air Ambulance: he has flown more than 500 missions for the East Anglian Air Ambulance service.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="pete-smart-wiltshire"&gt;62. Pete Smart (Wiltshire)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Volunteer groundsman and coach Pete wins the award for his work in youth football. As well as painting over 5,000 miles of lines for football pitches, he’s now training the grandchildren of people he coached when he was younger.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="jackie-patton-county-down"&gt;63. Jackie Patton (County Down)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jackie becomes the first person in Northern Ireland to win the award; her volunteering efforts brought a major world championship event to her local sailing club. Jackie coordinated a network of 60 volunteers, helping the club to expand and host events, including the prestigious Formula 18 Catamaran World Sailing Championships.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="jess-starns-berkshire"&gt;64. Jess Starns (Berkshire)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jess wins the award for setting up &lt;a rel="external" href="http://dyspraxic.me.uk/"&gt;Dyspraxic Me&lt;/a&gt;. Inspired by her personal experience of living with dyspraxia, Jess also organises speakers, trainers and guests for Dyspraxic Me events, helping many young people with dyspraxia improve their personal and work skills.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="dave-brook-leeds"&gt;65. Dave Brook (Leeds)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dave wins the award for setting up his own gang resistance programme, ‘Karate for Inner City Kids’ (KICK) to help young people develop a healthier lifestyle away from the influence of crime and drugs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="ron-andrew-manchester"&gt;66. Ron Andrew (Manchester)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ron wins the award for tending the graves of local soldiers who fought in the First or Second World War. Ron, a former drum major, spends his time and his own money cleaning headstones and buying flowers and urns to make sure those who gave so much are not forgotten.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="frank-blades-lincolnshire"&gt;67. Frank Blades (Lincolnshire)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After his wife was discharged from hospital Frank became her carer, but felt that they had been sent home without adequate support or advice. Frank wins the award for campaigning about issues that carers face; his work led to all the Lincolnshire Healthcare Trust hospitals introducing a new Carers Policy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="jean-wilson-worcester"&gt;68. Jean Wilson (Worcester)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jean wins the award for founding the charity &lt;a rel="external" href="http://www.newhopeworcester.co.uk/index.aspx?redirect=true&amp;amp;infoid=1"&gt;New Hope.&lt;/a&gt; New Hope supports the families of local children who have disabilities and complex health care needs. Jean founded the group in 2010 when she discovered that there was little support in her area for her daughter Emily, who was diagnosed with a severe disability at 17 months old.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="yvonne-obura-salisbury"&gt;69. Yvonne Obura (Salisbury)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yvonne wins the award for raising awareness of Female Genital Mutilation (&lt;abbr title="Female Genital Mutilation"&gt;FGM&lt;/abbr&gt;) amongst UK doctors. Realising that their knowledge of &lt;abbr title="Female Genital Mutilation"&gt;FGM&lt;/abbr&gt; was low, she volunteered through the charity Orchid Project, helping to develop training materials and guidance for doctors on how to approach cases of &lt;abbr title="Female Genital Mutilation"&gt;FGM&lt;/abbr&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="lauren-eaves-st-albans"&gt;70. Lauren Eaves (St Albans)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lauren wins the award for her campaigning against child marriage. Lauren volunteers as a youth advisor and ambassador for &lt;a rel="external" href="http://www.plan-uk.org/"&gt;Plan UK,&lt;/a&gt; a charity that works with the world’s poorest children so they can move themselves from a life of poverty to a future with opportunity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="jenny-thomson-aberdeen"&gt;71. Jenny Thomson (Aberdeen)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jenny wins the award for her volunteering work at both the 1970 Commonwealth Games in Edinburgh and now the 2014 games in Glasgow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="jackie-murphy-london"&gt;72. Jackie Murphy (London)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pearly Queen Jackie has carried on the traditions of her ancestors – who were first crowned Pearly Kings and Queens in 1894 – by raising thousands of pounds for charity. Recently she helped raise £65,000 so that primary school students from a local special needs school will have access to a swimming pool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="sue-ransley-west-sussex"&gt;73. Sue Ransley (West Sussex)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sue led the way in a large community effort that saw her village get a new local store. With a troop of volunteers, Sue raised almost £250,000 to buy a building in the village and then transformed it into an attractive shop premises.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:www.gov.uk,2005:NewsArticlePresenter/251554</id>
    <published>2014-07-28T12:30:09+01:00</published>
    <updated>2014-07-28T12:30:09+01:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/eid-al-fitr-2014-prime-ministers-message"/>
    <title>News story: Eid al-Fitr 2014: Prime Minister's message</title>
    <category label="News story" term="News story"/>
    <summary>David Cameron has recorded a video message for Eid al-Fitr to wish Muslims in the UK and around the world "Eid Mubarak".</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class="govspeak"&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel="external" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ZcsCIuHAyOA"&gt;Eid al-Fitr 2014: David Cameron’s message&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="video-transcript"&gt;Video transcript&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I want to send my best wishes to Muslims across the country and around the world celebrating Eid. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This Ramadan, British Muslims have shown what Islam is all about. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve seen an inspiring amount of charity - with Muslims across the country giving what they can and giving up their own time for those less fortunate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve seen a commitment to contemplation - and Muslims have been putting themselves second as they pray, abstain and fast during the holy month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Third, we’ve seen a dedication to community - and once again this year British Muslims have opened their doors to those of all backgrounds as part of the Big Iftar, breaking bread and breaking down barriers in mosques, in community centres, in parks – even at a synagogue in north London. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s been a challenging month – especially during those long summer days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So it is fantastic to see so many British Muslims –and those of other faiths and none – come together to celebrate at this special time. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once again, to everyone who is celebrating, Eid Mubarak. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:www.gov.uk,2005:NewsArticlePresenter/251785</id>
    <published>2014-07-28T00:15:16+01:00</published>
    <updated>2014-07-28T00:15:16+01:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/world-hepatitis-day-2014-david-camerons-message"/>
    <title>News story: World Hepatitis Day 2014: David Cameron’s message</title>
    <category label="News story" term="News story"/>
    <summary>The Prime Minister has issued a statement for World Hepatitis Day 2014.</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class="govspeak"&gt;&lt;p&gt;David Cameron said:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Hepatitis C is a treatable and curable virus, and yet deaths from this disease are continuing to rise. We are committed to fighting this as part of our work to reduce premature mortality from liver disease, so it is crucial that awareness is improved and that more people are tested and diagnosed early in order to access life-saving treatments.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p class="last-child"&gt;Significant progress has been made recently in tackling hepatitis C, including this government’s introduction of an opt-out blood borne virus testing policy in prisons. Today, on World Hepatitis Day, 28 July 2014, I urge the continuation of this good work to improve the awareness and testing of hepatitis C, and call on anyone who might be at risk to get tested.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:www.gov.uk,2005:NewsArticlePresenter/249327</id>
    <published>2014-07-24T10:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2014-07-24T10:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/regius-professor-of-hebrew-oxford-university-jan-joosten"/>
    <title>Press release: Regius Professor of Hebrew, Oxford University: Jan Joosten</title>
    <category label="Press release" term="Press release"/>
    <summary>The Queen has approved that Professor Jan Joosten be appointed Regius Professor of Hebrew in the University of Oxford.</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class="govspeak"&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Queen has approved that Professor Jan Joosten ThM, PhD, Professor of Old Testament Exegesis at the University of Strasbourg, be appointed Regius Professor of Hebrew in the University of Oxford in succession to Professor Hugh Williamson, MA PhD DD Camb DD Oxf FBA, who retires on 30 September.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="professor-jan-joosten"&gt;Professor Jan Joosten&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Professor Joosten (55) has been Professor of Old Testament Exegesis at the University of Strasbourg since 2004, before which he was Professor of Biblical Philology (1994-2004). Prior to this he was Lecturer in Biblical Hebrew at the Faculty of Protestant Theology in Brussels (1991-94), Pastor of the United Protestant Church in Belgium (1988-94) and Lecturer of Old Testament at the École de Théologie in Butare, Rwanda (1985-87).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Professor Joosten was born in Belgium and holds degrees in Theology from the Faculty of Protestant Theology in Brussels (1981) and from Princeton (1982), and doctorates from the Hebrew University of Jerusalem (1989) and Brussels (1994). He has a considerable international reputation in the field of Old Testament / Hebrew Bible engaging particularly with Biblical Hebrew Syntax, the Septuagint, and Old Testament exegetical questions.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:www.gov.uk,2005:SpeechPresenter/251379</id>
    <published>2014-07-23T15:12:38+01:00</published>
    <updated>2014-07-23T15:12:38+01:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.gov.uk/government/speeches/prime-ministers-speech-commonwealth-games-business-conference"/>
    <title>Speech: Prime Minister’s speech: Commonwealth Games Business Conference</title>
    <category label="Speech" term="Speech"/>
    <summary>Held prior to the Opening Ceremony, the conference will be the main focus of the business programme during the 2014 Commonwealth Games.</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class="govspeak"&gt;&lt;p&gt;It’s fantastic to be here in Glasgow today. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The athletes are arriving, the venues are ready, the crowds are gearing up and we’re looking forward to a fantastic Commonwealth Games. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For us, the legacy of these Games won’t just be measured in medals won or records broken – though of course those things are great.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It will be measured in young lives inspired, Glasgow promoted to the world – and yes, in deals done, contracts won, businesses boosted and jobs created. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remember: at London 2012 we didn’t just win 65 medals, we switched the world back on to London and the UK – and won £14 billion for the economy, in sales, investments and contracts. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s the British way: going for gold in all its forms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that’s what these Games are about, too: showing the UK off to the world. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now I’ve been accused of being a salesman before; frankly I take that as a compliment not an insult. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I see it as a big part of my job to sell the UK: to bang the drum for our businesses, and that’s what I’m here to do today. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I want to set out the 3 big commitments we have made to make Britain such a good place to invest, to partner with and to do business with. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So commitment 1: making Britain the world’s most open and welcoming economy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This country is the largest destination for foreign direct investment in Europe. That didn’t just happen by accident. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Investors didn’t just close their eyes a stick a pin in a map.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They opened their eyes and saw an open, welcoming economy with a corporation tax which - at 21% - is set to be the lowest in the G7, a Patent Box that slashes taxes for those developing new products and making them here and a generous tax relief for research and development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They saw historic levels of investment in infrastructure, too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right here in Scotland we’ve got a &lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/city-deal-glasgow-and-clyde-valley"&gt;£1 billion city deal for Glasgow&lt;/a&gt;, a £230 million loan guarantee for Grangemouth and £100 million investment to extend rural broadband from Eyemouth to Stromness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is taking place right across the UK. We’ve got the biggest construction project in Europe going on under London in &lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/policies/expanding-and-improving-the-rail-network/supporting-pages/developing-crossrail"&gt;Crossrail&lt;/a&gt;. We’ve given the green light to a new high-speed north-south rail line and we’ve got &lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/policies/transforming-uk-broadband"&gt;superfast broadband&lt;/a&gt; spreading all over our country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And when you add all this to the UK’s other advantages: our time zone, the fact that we speak the world’s global language, that we have some of the best universities in the world – not least Glasgow, Edinburgh, St Andrews, Stirling – that we have Scotland’s wind and waves, its oil and gas and its creativity and innovation then you have a truly enticing prospect for any international investor. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s why we’ve seen foreign direct investment going up and up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s why we saw a record-breaking 1,773 projects funded by foreign investors last year like the Swedish company Vattenfall building wind farms in Wales, like Australia’s Wolf Minerals investing in metal exploration in Devon and like Belgian payments firm Clear2pay expanding its base here in Scotland.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Indeed, foreign investment in UK assets is now 63% of our GDP with Malaysia helping to rebuild our cities, India investing in our cars and Dubai working on our ports.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Look at the North Sea and it’s not just the UK investing in our oil and gas industry – it’s Norway and the UAE.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Look at Silicon Glen and it’s not just Britain funding the latest technology – it’s America and Switzerland.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Look at the Moray Firth, and it’s not just local companies ploughing money into offshore wind – it’s Japan and Spain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today foreign investment in the UK is at its highest level since records began.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But that’s not a reason to rest on our laurels – it’s a reason to go even further. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And we are – the investment keeps rolling in with CGI almost doubling its Glasgow workforce, Kaiam Corporation building a new production facility in Livingston and SAS, Wipro and Clough all expanding and creating more jobs right here in the UK.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And talking of investment, I’m delighted that Flybe has today announced that it is investing in a new route launching daily flights from Aberdeen to London City later this year and keeping connected the thriving economy of north-east Scotland.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Commitment 2 has been to promote trade and industry around the world. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I came into government I walked over to the Foreign and Commonwealth Office and I said ‘your job description is changing’. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To our diplomats I said ‘you’re not just ambassadors for the UK – you’re ambassadors for UK PLC’. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To our ministers I said ‘you’re not just representing UK government – you’re representing UK business’.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Where British foreign policy was in retreat, it is now on the advance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Where trade was seen as secondary, it is now at the heart of our diplomacy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Where Britain was focusing on its continental neighbours rather than its Commonwealth friends, exports to non-EU countries have increased by nearly 19%.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Foreign and Commonwealth Office has been a big part of connecting us with the fastest growing parts of the world – and yes, that includes the Commonwealth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve increased our diplomatic presence in India – now bigger than any other country’s, including America – and only this month we announced a new deputy high commission in Ahmedabad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve expanded our reach in Turkey, Mexico, Indonesia, Burma, Thailand, Mongolia, Nigeria and more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve taken trade delegations around the world, from Brazil to Malaysia, with business people from around the UK, including Aggreko and Standard Life from here in Scotland.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And with UKTI we’ve been running a totally unprecedented campaign – the GREAT campaign – emblazoning the Union flag from the skyscrapers of Dubai to the tuk tuks of Cambodia and telling people that Great Britain is a great place to do business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And all this is working. Our exports to China are up by 115%, to India by 55%.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is a golden era for UK exports, driven by our luxury brands.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To give you just one example from here in Scotland – Scotch whisky is selling at record levels from America to China to Russia to the Gulf. In fact sales are now worth £135 a second to the UK balance of trade.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The prizes for businesses in Scotland and across the UK are incredible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s why I’ll keep on flying the flag for Britain every chance I can.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And commitment 3: backing the UK’s strengths.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My industrial policy is clear. I don’t believe in picking winners, but I do believe in backing them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wherever the UK has a strength, we will build on it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wherever we have an advantage, we will use it. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You only have to look around Scotland to see some of the big strengths we have in this country. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s Clyde Space, where they’ve launched one of the smallest satellites to go into space. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Up in the Rosyth shipyard there’s the largest aircraft carrier in history, HMS Queen Elizabeth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Edinburgh the city’s getting a name as a global hub for tech start-ups.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Aberdeen they’re taking the expertise, won through years of deep sea exploration, and applying it to creating the newest sources of green energy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the UK’s greatest strengths is financial services.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a Scottish strength, too, supporting 200,000 jobs here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And there is an inextricable link between the success of the City of London and the globally renowned financial centres of Edinburgh, Aberdeen, Dundee and Glasgow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We as a government don’t just see these industries and think ‘fantastic, let the tax revenue roll in’.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are an unashamedly activist government.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And to back Scotland’s biggest success stories we’re doing everything we can – removing the barriers to selling Scottish whisky around the world, giving decommissioning relief to the oil industry and reducing taxes for the film and gaming industries. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That is our commitment: to take the giants of British industry and make them greater still.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’d like to end by saying this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Commonwealth has a great history of trade.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are, after all, a common wealth, not just united by history, culture and values but by trade and prosperity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And the UK – with Scotland at its heart – has a great history of trade, too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the country of great inventors like Alexander Graham Bell, who made the telephone and exported it to the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s the country of great thinkers like Adam Smith, who paved the way for modern industrial economies and of textile merchants like Alexander Chalmers, whose trading relationship with Poland was so close that he ended up living there and becoming Mayor of Warsaw.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And together – we can have a great future, too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are committed to achieving that, by creating that open, welcoming economy by promoting that trade and industry around the world and by getting full square behind our great UK industries so we can make them even greater.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All we need you to do is to come here, and to invest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So welcome to Scotland – and enjoy the Games.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:www.gov.uk,2005:NewsArticlePresenter/250741</id>
    <published>2014-07-23T00:15:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2014-07-23T00:15:00+01:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/turning-the-games-into-gold-economic-boost-from-london-2012-has-passed-14-billion"/>
    <title>Press release: Turning the Games into gold: economic boost from London 2012  has passed £14 billion</title>
    <category label="Press release" term="Press release"/>
    <summary>The trade and industry boost following the London 2012 Olympic and Paralympic Games has beaten the 4 year target in half the time.</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class="govspeak"&gt;&lt;p&gt;The UK economy has seen a trade and industry boost in excess of £14 billion following the London 2012 Olympic and Paralympic Games, beating the 4 year target of £11 billion in half the time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the &lt;a rel="external" href="http://www.glasgow2014.com/"&gt;Commonwealth Games&lt;/a&gt; opens in Glasgow, the second annual report on the successful legacy from the London 2012 Olympic and Paralympic Games has been released. It highlights how hosting major sports events can bring about benefits that improve people’s lives and help sell the best of Britain to the world. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The £14.2 billion comes from businesses securing contract wins, additional sales and new foreign investment in the 2 years since UKTI’s British Business Embassy at Lancaster House hosted the largest programme of business events held in Britain during London 2012.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today (23 July) the Prime Minister will address business and Commonwealth leaders in Glasgow. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Prime Minister will say: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Part of &lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/topics/uk-economy"&gt;our long-term economic plan&lt;/a&gt; is about promoting every part of our country to the world and Glasgow’s Commonwealth Games will give us another fantastic platform to do this.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;It follows on from London 2012, which was not just an amazing sporting event, but also a great opportunity to secure a lasting economic and sporting legacy for the whole UK.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;This government will continue to work on behalf of every hardworking business in the UK to drum up trade, encourage investment and pave the way for growth so we can generate jobs, pay our way in the world, and create stability, security and a brighter future for our country.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p class="last-child"&gt;I am confident we can build on our experience in London and make Glasgow 2014 so much more than just an amazing sporting event.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The announcement coincides with news that British companies have reported an expected £7 billion of overseas business in Commonwealth countries as a result of UKTI support.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="new-trade-and-investment-deals-worth-over-200-million"&gt;New trade and investment deals worth over £200 million&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Prime Minister will also announce new trade and investment deals worth over £200 million, creating or safeguarding more than 500 UK jobs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Sunday UKTI published record-breaking Foreign Direct Investment results for 2013/14, with 1,773 projects spread across the UK and 14% more than the previous year, creating 66,390 jobs – the highest in over a decade – and safeguarding 44,971.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Secretary of State for Culture, Media and Sport, Sajid Javid, said:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p class="last-child"&gt;The legacy from the London 2012 Olympic and Paralympic Games is going from strength to strength with the economic, sporting and social benefits being felt by communities across the country. I am sure that the legacy from Glasgow 2014 will build on this further and that the Commonwealth Games in Glasgow will be a fantastic event that inspires many to get involved in sport.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Business Secretary, Vince Cable, said:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p class="last-child"&gt;The delivery of London 2012 on time and on budget led to hosting nations turning to the UK to help deliver their own events with supply opportunities running into the billions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p class="last-child"&gt;UK Trade &amp;amp; Investment has played a key role in helping British companies maximise these opportunities and the result is a £14 billion boost to the UK economy from the Games.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p class="last-child"&gt;The UK’s future prosperity will not come from relying on domestic markets alone and during the Commonwealth Games we are giving another major push to encourage firms across the UK to sell overseas and foreign businesses to invest here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lord Sebastian Coe, the Prime Minister’s Olympic and Paralympic Legacy Ambassador, said:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p class="last-child"&gt;This report shows just how much is happening across the country to keep the spirit of London 2012 alive 2 years on from the Games. The country has taken the inspirational performances of our athletes and the uplifting public spirit seen during those few weeks in 2012, and built on it, whether through community projects, volunteering, and new sporting facilities, or through new ways of working together and improved trade relationships.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p class="last-child"&gt;This report celebrates some of those achievements, but there are many more examples happening all across the country. I look forward to the next 12 months of this legacy journey.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Mayor of London, Boris Johnson, said: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p class="last-child"&gt;By common consent, London wowed the world when it staged the 2012 Olympic and Paralympic Games. 2 years on from that golden summer we are accelerating the transformation of Stratford and beyond. Queen Elizabeth Olympic Park is now reopened and ambitious plans are in place to develop a constellation of educational, artistic, technology and cultural institutions on the site to strengthen our lead as a global force in these sectors and deliver tens of thousands of jobs. This is a living legacy that is reaping economic and social dividends not just here in London but across the UK.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id="legacy"&gt;Legacy&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id="economic-legacy"&gt;Economic legacy&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;UK firms winning contracts to help stage major sporting events. £150 million worth of business won by 40 companies for the Brazil 2014 World Cup and Rio 2016 Olympics.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;International visits to the UK increased by 6% in 2013 to 33 million with a 13% increase in visitor spend to £21 billion.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3 id="sport-and-healthy-living-legacy"&gt;Sport and healthy living legacy&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;More people playing sport than ever before. 15.6 million people aged 16 and over play sport once a week – 1.7 million more than in 2005 when London won the bid to host the Games. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;An additional year’s funding for primary school sport, bringing the total investment to over £450 million from September 2013, ensuring that children get an excellent experience of sport early on in life.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;A new £18 million National Lottery fund launched to improve sports facilities in primary schools. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Over 16,000 community sports facilities upgraded to date through Sport England’s Inspired Facilities Fund.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The government and Mayor of London’s ‘Moving More, Living More’ initiative launched to promote tackling physical inactivity.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3 id="regeneration-of-east-london"&gt;Regeneration of East London&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Transformation of Queen Elizabeth Olympic Park complete, parkland and venues re-opened and stadium conversion work underway.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;More than 1 million visitors to Queen Elizabeth Olympic Park since it reopened.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;2,800 homes converted from athletes’ village to residential housing. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;875 students attending the new Chobham Academy.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;New educational and cultural facilities planned for Queen Elizabeth Olympic Park, supported by Victoria and Albert Museum and University College London.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3 id="bringing-communities-together"&gt;Bringing communities together&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Strong volunteering legacy: ‘Join In’ supported 10,000 local events across the country in summer 2013. Rugby League World Cup 2013 and Tour de France Grand Depart 2014 recruited a total of 17,000 volunteers. Rugby World Cup 2015 recruiting 6,000 volunteers.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Spirit of 2012 Trust established in November 2013 by Big Lottery Fund, with endowment of £46 million, using proceeds from the sale of the Olympic and Paralympic Athletes’ Village to support sport, arts and volunteering projects across the country.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3 id="paralympic-legacy"&gt;Paralympic legacy&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Sport England committed to investing over £170 million in disability sport between 2013 and 2017.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;National Paralympic Day held on Queen Elizabeth Olympic Park.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Stoke Mandeville to have a role in all future Paralympic flame ceremonies.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Disability Confident Campaign to help employers tackle barriers to employing disabled people.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2 id="trade-and-investment"&gt;Trade and investment&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trade and investment deals between UK and overseas companies announced on Wednesday at the conference include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="trade"&gt;Trade&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Neal’s Yard Remedies, a leading UK organic health and beauty care provider who manufactures in Dorset, has announced a 10 year franchise agreement with Starluxe to open 20 stores in Korea to bring in £10 million over the next 5 years.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rochdale-based Precision Technologies Group has secured £3.85 million in export orders to one of China’s leading specialists in ice systems and industrial cooling technologies and Taiwan’s premier air and refrigeration compressor specialists.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Marketing agency Seven has expanded its portfolio to Portugal and is expecting to increase revenues by £2 million over the next 3 years. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cheshire-based software company ICC Solutions has announced a £20 million contract to deliver chip and pin test tools and certification services to the US. The move will create up to 50 UK jobs.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Standard Life investments has confirmed £12 million worth of new contracts over the last year following the support and advice of UKTI.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;London-based manufacturing firm, CP Cases, has recently won £1.5 million in contracts, creating 5 new UK jobs to supply high-performance cases and racks to India, Italy, the UAE and South Korea.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Nottingham-based business consultancy M4 Management has announced wins of £1.3 million in Poland and expects a further £2.5 million of deals in India, China and the USA, creating 5 new jobs.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;London-based Trueform Engineering Limited has recently been awarded a major contract to deliver high-quality bus shelter infrastructure throughout the kingdom of Bahrain. As a result of this and wider international expansion into the Middle Eastern market, Trueform expect their revenue to increase by at least £6 million and create 10 additional UK jobs in the manufacturing engineering sector over the next 3 years.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Skin care company Bulldog, which produces exclusively for men, has predicted £10 million of export sales and up to 20 new jobs after a number of business wins, predominantly in Sweden.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3 id="inward-investment"&gt;Inward investment&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Leading Japanese ICT company KDDI is investing a further £135 million into Telehouse’s data centre campus at London Docklands.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Samsung has announced it will create 358 customer support jobs in Leeds at a new customer call centre based in Claypit Lane.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;US advertising company Intent Media is investing £5 million to open an office in London creating 50 new jobs over the next 2 years. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;US media buyers Accordant Media is to set up their first UK office, outside the USA, in Soho, creating up to 30 jobs and adding an estimated £3 million to the UK economy.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;French Technology firm Sofyne Active Technology have been working with UKTI to expand into the UK, USA and China markets. As a result of this, Sofyne will be opening a third UK office in 2015. Growth of over 50 new jobs in the UK, US and China, is expected to increase Sofyne’s revenues by £5 million in the next 3 years.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Commonwealth Games Business Conference is the first of 2 events dedicated to promoting UK businesses during the high profile sporting events. The British Business House, run by UKTI, is a 3-day conference dedicated to showcasing to business and political leaders the ‘Best of British’. It will also provide a base for businesses, ministers and industry leaders to take part in roundtable discussions, sector-themed seminars hosted by ministers and networking opportunities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="notes-to-editors"&gt;Notes to editors&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Read about &lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/commonwealth-games-business-conference-and-british-business-house"&gt;the Commonwealth Games Business Conference and the British Business House&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The British Business House runs at the Glasgow City Chambers from 23 to 25 July. Its objectives are to:
    &lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;develop trade opportunities for UK companies internationally&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;promote inward investment into the UK&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;showcase the Best of British business in priority sectors&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;attract a high calibre international and domestic business audience&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;bring decision makers from around the Commonwealth together to undertake business in the UK&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;provide an exclusive base for business leaders and ministers&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;complement activity at Scotland House&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;UKTI has helped many UK companies take advantage of opportunities in the Commonwealth market. These include:
    &lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Courageous Success, an HR training company based in Lincolnshire, who joined UKTI’s Passport to Export scheme and worked with UKTI in Sydney to get their first orders in Australia. Their Australian orders are now projected to account for 15% of their turnover this year.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Goody Good Stuff, a vegetarian sweets company based in Lancashire, who joined UKTI’s Passport to Export which helped them to export abroad to Commonwealth countries including Malta, Australia, Hong Kong, Singapore and Canada. The award-winning company now attributes 70% of its business to exports.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;For more case studies, please contact UKTI press office.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/UKTI-inward-investment-report-2013-2014"&gt;UKTI’s Inward Investment Annual Report&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;To see the full Olympics Legacy Report, contact DCMS on 020 7211 6971&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;An infographic showing the business opportunities with Commonwealth countries can be &lt;a rel="external" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/ukti/14707326521/"&gt;downloaded&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;UK Trade &amp;amp; Investment (UKTI) is the government department that helps UK-based companies succeed in the global economy. We also help overseas companies bring their high quality investment to the UK’s economy – acknowledged as Europe’s best place from which to succeed in global business. UKTI offers expertise and contacts through its extensive network of specialists in the UK, and in British embassies and other diplomatic offices around the world. We provide companies with the tools they require to be competitive on the world stage. &lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/ukti"&gt;More information on UKTI&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:www.gov.uk,2005:SpeechPresenter/251225</id>
    <published>2014-07-22T17:35:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2014-07-22T17:35:00+01:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.gov.uk/government/speeches/girl-summit-2014-david-camerons-speech"/>
    <title>Speech: Girl Summit 2014: David Cameron's speech</title>
    <category label="Speech" term="Speech"/>
    <summary>David Cameron's speech from the 2014 Girl Summit held in London.</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class="govspeak"&gt;&lt;figure class="image embedded"&gt;&lt;div class="img"&gt;&lt;img alt="David Cameron speaking at the Girl Summit" src="https://assets.digital.cabinet-office.gov.uk/government/uploads/system/uploads/image_data/file/28940/GirlSummit_govuk.jpg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;Well thank you very much Tony and thank you ladies and gentleman.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m absolutely delighted that Britain is hosting this conference. It comes in a year where I hope we’re doing everything we can to demonstrate how much we care about these issues. Justine Greening, Secretary of State for International Development, has put women and girls and equality right at the heart of our aid program. I know you heard from Theresa May, the Home Secretary, who is introducing really important legislation this year to tackle modern slavery, and, until recently our Foreign Secretary, William Hague, did a great job at putting front and centre the importance of preventing sexual violence in conflict.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So this conference today should be seen in that context. These are vitally important issues we’re addressing and I’m really proud that Britain is determined to play her part.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I want to say a few thank-yous. I think, let’s start with thanking the Walworth Academy for hosting us so brilliantly. A big thank you to you. I want to thank the 50 countries that are taking part, the NGOs, the faith organisations, civil society, I want to thank all of you for coming today and making this such an energetic and important conference. But I want to say a particular thank you to those people who have experience of &lt;abbr title="female genital mutilation"&gt;FGM&lt;/abbr&gt; or early and forced marriage who’ve spoken out. It takes huge bravery to do that and I want to thank you for doing that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I go to lots of conferences and events and seminars and think tanks and all the rest of it, and sometimes you sit there and you’re not quite sure what you’re trying to achieve. Here, it is absolutely clear about what we are trying to achieve, it is such a simple but noble and good ambition, and that is to outlaw the practices of female genital mutilation (&lt;abbr title="female genital mutilation"&gt;FGM&lt;/abbr&gt;) and childhood and early forced marriage, to outlaw them everywhere, for everyone within this generation. That is the aim. That is the ambition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, Britain doesn’t have any special magic. We wanted to host this conference because we wanted to bring people together. We’re proud of our record on aid and development. We’re proud that we kept our promises to the poorest people in the world. We’re one of the few countries that have met our aim of 0.7% of our GDP, but we don’t pretend any special knowledge or any special magic. We just wanted to bring people together and see what we could do to help, with the power of convening people to come up with ideas and commitments to outlaw these practices. That is what today is all about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But for me the context is very simple. The context is about equality. I’m a dad with 3 children, 2 girls and a boy, and I want my girls to grow up with every opportunity that my son has, with no disadvantage, with the chance to make everything that my girls can of their lives. And that is really what this is, it’s about equality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And there – of course, there are so many things, when it comes to tackling inequality, we need to address, whether it is equal pay or equal rights or fighting discrimination or equal opportunities, including in political life. But what seems to me is so important about these 2 issues is they are absolutely standing rebukes to our world that they still exist. And so when we think of the fight for equality, which should be at the heart of the commitments to the Millennium Development Goals, it’s absolutely clear to me that we’ve got to start with outlawing these practices, which is why today’s conference is so important.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now when we make commitments like this, I think we have to ask ourselves 3 very straightforward questions: why give these issues such a priority? How are we going to achieve our goals? And, crucially, what we are about to do – will it work? And how are we going to follow up on the promises that we make?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now the why, I think, is simple. These practices aren’t just simply a violation of girls’ rights. They are a total violation of the chance to enjoy your childhood and the chance to lead a fulfilling life. That is why these issues matter so much.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And the figures are so shocking. Here in the United Kingdom, 130,000 people affected by &lt;abbr title="female genital mutilation"&gt;FGM&lt;/abbr&gt;. 60,000 girls under the age of 15 potentially at risk. And then when we consider the global figures: 130 million women in our world affected by &lt;abbr title="female genital mutilation"&gt;FGM&lt;/abbr&gt; and 63 million more potentially at risk by 2050.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And when we look at the problems of childhood and early forced marriage, in our world today, 700 million people married as children, and a further 280 million at risk. When we think of the great development challenges that we face, of eradicating poverty, of dealing with diseases – malaria, TB, polio – this ranks alongside that in terms of the scale of the challenge that we face and the scale of the ambition that we need in order to defeat it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But, above all, in answering the question, ‘Why these 2 issues?’ I would argue that we are dealing with a preventable evil. This does not have to happen. And with the right combination of effort, political will and hard work, we can achieve what we have set out to achieve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So how do we do it? Well, I think this charter that countries have signed today and organisations are signing today is so simple and clear, written in plain language, very clear commitments that people and countries are making, and I think what is so good about it is that it understands the fundamental point that simply passing a law, or simply spending some money, is not enough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Politicians are very good at passing laws – we’re also quite good at spending money – but what politicians aren’t always good at is following through and making sure that a change in law leads to a change in culture, leads to a change in practice, and that is why I think this charter, with all the commitments it makes for what countries and families and people must do, is so good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And here in Britain, we want to be good to our word. It is already illegal to marry as a child. It is already illegal to push someone into a forced marriage. It’s already illegal to take part in female genital mutilation. But that’s not enough, and so I can tell you today about the pledges we are making, that we are saying it will now be a &lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/pm-hosts-girl-summit-2014-a-future-free-from-fgm-and-child-and-forced-marriage"&gt;mandatory duty for doctors and teachers and others to report when these things happen&lt;/a&gt; so that we can put a stop to it, and for the first time, we’re going to legislate so that parents are liable if they allow their daughters to be cut.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, added to this are the funds that we’ll provide, both here, domestically in the UK, and £25 million to international help in terms of childhood and forced marriage and £35 million commitment to help fight &lt;abbr title="female genital mutilation"&gt;FGM&lt;/abbr&gt; internationally. I believe if we adopt this charter, if we use it as a campaigning vehicle to start the campaign now and all over the world, we can achieve the goals that we have.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So to that final question: will it work? Well, we’ve already got 230 signatures. We’ve already got 21 governments that have made that commitment. But, as Tony said, what this has got to be about is building a global movement: a global movement that doesn’t end here, a global movement that starts here and a global movement that we can follow up, monitoring what the countries have done who signed this, what the organisations have done who have signed this, to check that people keep their promises, to check that we don’t just change the law we change the culture, to check that we follow up on every single commitment that we’ve made.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve told you about my children. So my daughter – my eldest daughter is 10; not that much younger than some of the children who get pushed into childhood or early marriage; not that much younger than girls who get cut and have their lives, in so many ways, taken away from them. And this really is about the world that we want children like my daughter to grow up in. Is it going to be a world where we recognise that these practices are unacceptable, but instead of just saying that, instead of just signing declarations, instead of just passing laws, we actually commit to do everything we can, in our own countries and globally, to outlaw these practices forever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That is the commitment that Britain makes. That is the commitment that the 21 countries have made. Now let us take this campaign, let us run it globally, and let us outlaw these practices and improve the state of our world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
